Hey guys, Pastor Myers here and um
I am uh just jumping on tonight to uh
continue what looks like will be a
tradition uh from here on out. Uh last
year at this time
um we had just lost my brother and um I
jumped on to YouTube and shared
Heaven's Diary um live for everyone to
be able to hear it. And that was in
honor of my brother. Um last year it was
Heaven's Diary part one. So we're going
to do the same thing again tonight.
Uh but this time we're going to do part
one and part two.
Uh last year this time part two may have
been completed but it was not ready.
Uh but now I'm going to be I'm releasing
part two to the public to be able to to
see the full thing um like I did with
part one.
And uh my prayer is that it will bless
you. Uh for those of you that have lost
loved ones
um for all of us who are looking forward
to uh the kingdom of heaven, um I pray
that this part two will bless you. Part
two, part one was about the journey to
heaven
um and the entrance into the city. Part
two
uh is about the millennium, the 10,00
years and the judgment that occurs
during that time and what heaven will be
like during that 10,00 years. And so
obviously part three is going to be what
life will be like on this earth made
new. Um I have not written that yet. Um,
honestly,
uh, the loss of my brother is still very
raw. So, I've just been unable,
um, to pick up
and, um, and write, but it is coming. It
will come, uh, at the right time.
And, uh, so we're going to go ahead,
guys, and play part one and part two
together. Uh, if you've heard part one
before, then you know this is going to
be the routine, right? Um, when part
three is ready, then we're going you
I'mma play the whole thing straight
through. So, it'll probably be like four
hours alto together. Um, that's when
part three is done. So anyway guys, I
hope this uh listen to this will
encourage you tonight and will encourage
you to
know that there is something better
after this.
So may God bless you as you listen to
Heaven's Diary part one which will be
followed immediately by part two.
Blessings y'all.
Awake. Awake. Daniel 12 1-3. The voice
pierces my ears, jolting me out of my
sleep. It would usually take me a few
[music] minutes to be fully alert after
a deep sleep, but not today. Unlike
anything I've ever heard, this piercing
voice resonates deep within me. As I
open my eyes, I realize I am in a
confined space [music] surrounded by
absolute darkness. My heart races and
suddenly thoughts flood my mind. My last
memory, it [music] seems like just
moments ago, were the tear stained faces
of family and my close friends, their
sorrowful embraces, [music] and the
somber prayers that were whispered on my
behalf as I was, "Yes, [music]
I was slipping into death." I recall my
last words, "Lord, please save me." I
remember that moment as doubts and fears
threatened to consume me. How I clung to
my faith that Christ's [music] sacrifice
had indeed covered me. That I would
stand before God with peace and live
again. Now in the darkness, a thought
takes hold [music] of me. The voice I
just heard is it. I can barely finish
the thought when suddenly the confined
[music] space begins to shake violently
and I feel an unimaginable force pulling
[music] me upward. The ground crumbles
around me and waves of dust fill the
air, propelling me upwards. [music] I
feel an indescribable surge of energy
course through my entire being. Light
floods my mind as if it is awakening to
powers unknown to me before. The clarity
of my eyesight stuns me. I look at my
hands [music] only to find that they are
no longer the hands I am familiar with.
1 Corinthians 15:es 50- 54. [music] They
glow. It is a radiant light. An
overwhelming energy pulsates [music] my
entire body. I gasp for my first breath.
And then I realize I have been
resurrected. [music] I've been snatched
from death's jaws. Oh death, where is
your sting? Oh grave, where is your
victory? My heart shouts. [music]
1 Corinthians 15:55.
I am aware that my senses have been
heightened. [music]
Suspended in the air, I take in the
incredible sights surrounding me. I look
[music] down to see graves exploding
open and countless people rising from
them, their bodies glowing with the same
newfound radiance as mine. 1
Thessalonians 4 [music] 13-6.
Millions of bodies are ejected from the
grave, reminding me of Jonah coming up
from the belly of the fish. These are
the redeemed from every age, those who
died in unwavering faith, believing that
Jesus [music] would come again to rescue
them from the clutches of death. John
14:es 1:3. And now it was actually
happening.
I am [music] overwhelmed by the sheer
beauty and power emanating from their
glorified bodies. They look regal like
an army [music] of kings and queens.
All traces of sin, [music] death, aging,
disease are gone. A radiant light above
us captures our attention. [music] It is
Jesus. We all bear a striking
resemblance to him. 1 John 3:2.
He is wrapped in a glorious [music]
flame of light which brightens the
midnight sky. Surrounding him is an
innumerable company [music] of chariots
which begin to streak toward us, leaving
blazing trails in the midnight sky.
Psalm 68 and verse [music] 17. This is
our redemption. I think to myself, one
of the angels of fire is heading
straight toward me. The angel extends
its [music] hand to me, and I grab hold
of it as this powerful being swings me
up unto his chariot of fire. The fire
does not burn me. I have a flashback
[music] of Shadrach, Mach, and Abednego
in the fiery furnace, where the fire had
no effect upon them. Daniel 3. I learned
that this is my guardian angel who was
commissioned to be by my side while I
had lived on earth. Psalms 34:7. [music]
I have many questions for him, but I
instinctively know that this is not the
time. My eyes sweep the sky, taking in
the scene of the multitude of redeemed
souls suspended midair, glorified. Then
my attention is turned to the people
still standing on the earth below us.
[music]
Some have faces full of dread,
Revelation 6:16,
while others have faces lighted up with
the glory of God. [music] Isaiah 25
and:9.
The same force that pulled us from the
grave now begins to lift these living
saints into the air. [music]
I realize that these are the ones who
are alive to see the Lord's coming
[music] and will not taste death but be
translated instead. 1 Thessalonians 4:1
17. They [music] too are swept up by the
chariots, their bodies transformed into
perfection [music] instantaneously.
They meet us in the air and a roar of
triumph erupts from the massive army in
the sky. As far as glorified eyes can
see, [music] the horizon is filled with
the followers of Christ like a massive
ring encircling the globe. As I observe
the earth, it is apparent [music] that
time has passed. At a glance, the world
appears more advanced than when I lived
[music] on it. A realization hits me. I
now understand that I have been asleep
[music] in the grave for almost two
centuries. But it felt like mere
seconds. [music] I knew and felt
nothing. Ecclesiastes 9:5, [music]
Psalms 115 and verse 17, Isaiah 38 and
verse [music] 1. The overwhelming peace
and relief that fills my soul cannot be
put into words. I see the same looks of
ecstatic joy mirrored on the faces of my
[music] fellow redeemed. We are speeding
upward with Christ leading the way. We
look back to witness the earth becoming
desolate before our very eyes. 2 Peter
3 10-12. Revelation 15-16.
Those who are not caught up with us are
destroyed by the flood of Christ's fiery
glory [music] just as it was in the days
of Noah. Matthew 24 38 and 39. Not a
[music] single person remains alive on
earth. Jeremiah 4:es 23-29.
Revelation [music]
20 5 and 6. The righteous have been
caught up in the clouds while the wicked
perish at the brightness of Jesus. They
have joined [music] those left in the
grave who had not made Christ their
hope. And then a sight on the [music]
earth that causes us to shudder. For the
first time, our eyes behold [music] the
unveiled persons of Satan and his fallen
angels. So many were led to believe that
he was merely a fictitious [music]
figure along with the Bible itself. But
now we were seeing him with [music] our
very own eyes. As we begin to move
upward, an invisible chain binds Satan
and his angels to the earth. Now
desolated [music]
by the glory of God, we are told by the
angels that Satan will be bound there
for 1,000 years with no one to tempt and
that [music] at the end of the thousand
years, we will return. at which point
Satan [music] will be loosed and the
wicked resurrected for one final
conflict concluding the battle of
Armageddon. Revelation 20 [music] verse
1-3 and 5-7. Our journey into eternity
has begun. We are headed to the place
[music] Christ has prepared for us. John
14 1-3 Revelation 20 and:4 [music] As we
leave the dark desolated earth behind
clothed in glorious white I begin to
think of my loved ones. [music] I wonder
about my family and my friends. Were
they left on earth, [music] destroyed by
the overwhelming glory? Or were they
among this redeemed caravan, transformed
by it?
I scan the immense crowd, a sea of faces
stretching as far as the eye can see.
The sheer scale of this gathering
astounds me, leaving me in awe of the
diversity and beauty before me. Each
pair of eyes tells a story. Each face
reflecting a unique background. As we
advance towards the majestic city of
God, the crowd stirs with a palpable
energy. In this vast congregation, I
witness a remarkable phenomenon
unfolding. A wave of joyous recognition
ripples through the crowd [music] like
an electric current as a symphony of
reunions plays out before my eyes. Loved
ones and dear friends, long separated by
time, distance, [music]
and death recognize one another.
Children ripped from their parents by
death are reunited with them, [music]
never to be parted again. In this crowd,
no one is a stranger, a loner. [music]
For us, this is a family reunion. Every
one of us is related [music] by the
blood of Christ. The tribes within the
tribe of the redeemed converge, creating
a tapestry [music] of love and unity
that defies human comprehension.
People [music] from every nation and
tribe are here. Revelation 7 and:9
we recognize heroes of faith. David,
Joshua, Abraham, Paul, and others within
the crowd. I wonder what Abraham and
Sarai must be thinking as they look at
the fulfillment of the promise [music]
that their seed would be as the dust of
the earth and the stars of the sky. And
now here we are literally raised out of
the dust of the earth and shining as
stars lighting up the midnight sky.
Genesis [music] 13:16, Genesis 15:5,
Daniel 12:4. With unyielding
anticipation, I searched this multitude,
[music] my gaze fixated on finding my
family. I remember countless
conversations [music] were spent
envisioning a joyous reunion in the
resurrection. Hopeful yet anxious,
[music] I continue my search amidst the
throng. Suddenly, a moment of shock hits
me. A surge of disbelief floods [music]
my being as I realize that my brother
who when I died had not given [music]
his life to the Lord is making his way
towards me. How miraculous this moment
feels. How unfathomable. Overwhelmed by
an immeasurable flood of joy. We [music]
navigate through the undulating crowd.
Every step bringing us closer to one
another without disrupting [music] the
caravan's seamless unity. Tears of joy
flow relentlessly down our cheeks. For
we know that this encounter [music] was
possible only because of Christ. Yet, as
I embrace him, I can't help [music] but
wonder about the hows and wise behind
his being here. My heart swells with
anticipation, knowing that we will have
ample time to share and discover the
miraculous transformation his life must
have undergone. But the joyous [music]
reunion does not end here, for my eyes
soon fall upon the rest of my family. My
[music] parents respplendant in heavenly
glory stand beside my other two siblings
and they with their spouses and
children. [music] A sense of
completeness washes over me. But some of
our loved ones are absent from this
divine gathering. To our astonishment,
some whom we believed had accepted
Christ remain unaccounted for, while
others whom many of the redeemed thought
were beyond hope, have found their place
among us.
Tears of joy and sorrow mingle from
amidst the redeemed. A collective
realization dawn upon us. The absence of
loved ones, friends, and neighbors. I
think of my best friend. She isn't here.
[music] After my own conversion, I would
often talk to her about the Lord, but
she never felt that religion was for
her. But because we knew each other from
childhood, we remained best friends,
even though our lifestyles differed
drastically. The thought of her missing
out on heaven hurt my soul. And I knew
that hurt was multiplied infinitely in
the heart of God, who was not willing
that any should perish. Second Peter
[music]
3:9.
Yet being in the presence of Christ
assures us that his wisdom surpasses our
limited understanding, [music] and he
has made no mistakes regarding who is
lost and who is saved. The questions
among us multiply and intertwine,
reverberating through the air as we
engage in heartfelt conversations within
the vast sea of people are those who do
not yet understand what is taking
[music] place. These had never heard of
Christ but had followed the prompings of
the Holy Spirit without knowing. [music]
They lived lives of self-sacrifice,
humility, and love for neighbor. These
had [music] the law written on their
hearts without having ever read or heard
of Jesus. Romans 2:es 14 [music] and 15.
Already they were asking others about
the one wrapped in glorious fire called
Jesus and especially [music] about the
wounds in his hands. Zechariah 13:16.
They will have much to learn and
understand and will be overwhelmed with
amazement [music] as they hear the
history of the man that has purchased
their salvation from the grave. It is
the first hour of eternity. Anticipation
[music] is coursing through our veins,
fueling our curiosity about the wonders
that lie ahead. As we traverse the
cosmos at the speed of light, time seems
to stand still, allowing us to marvel at
the breathtaking [music] wonders of the
universe as if on a celestial train ride
toward everlasting glory.
>> [music]
>> It is as though past events have been
repeated [music] in the present. And I
am a witness to this miraculous work of
God. Amidst the crowd in the distance,
[music] I catch a glimpse of Moses who
had come to Egypt long ago to liberate
the Israelites [music]
from their bondage. Through the power of
God, he brought down the mighty kingdom
of Egypt, [music] a feat that seemed
impossible. The plagues that swept
through the land brought desolation, and
only those who were covered by the blood
of the lamb were spared [music] from its
horrors. Now I stand in awe as I see a
similar story unfolding. But this time,
it is Jesus who has come to redeem us.
This is [music] not just history
repeating itself. It is the actuality of
salvation.
Jesus, like Moses, has come to [music]
our earthly Egypt, humbling those who
have exalted themselves and freeing us
from the bondage of the graves. He has
opened the heavens, and we, [music] like
the children of Israel crossing the
parted Red Sea, are now passing through
[music] the skies toward our heavenly
Canaan, our promised land. Like the
Exodus, [music]
there is a mixed multitude among us.
Some have never heard of Christ. Some
heard and rejected him, but cried out to
him in the final moments of their lives.
Others [music] had dramatic conversion
stories, and still others had been
brought up to believe in him since they
were children. But all realized that
they were there only by the grace of
God, not by anything they had done or
not done. Ephesians 2:es 6-9. But unlike
the Exodus, this journey is not through
a desolate wilderness. We are traversing
vast universes, witnessing the beauty of
inhabited worlds. [music] Hebrews 1:2
and 11:3.
It is a surreal experience filled with
childlike [music] wonderment. We cannot
help but ask our angels about these
worlds. Who resides there? What do they
look like? What are they doing? How long
have they been there hidden from our
sight? But the angels reassure us that
we will have eternity to explore and
uncover these mysteries of God's
creation. We are overwhelmed by their
majesty as we gaze at these distant
[music] planets. Their beauty surpasses
anything we had seen on the earth which
had been tarnished by sin. Yet deep
within us we know that the city we are
journeying towards far surpasses even
[music] this splendor. We long to reach
the kingdom of God where we are told a
grand celebration, a [music] supper and
a coronation await us. Our capacity to
appreciate the magnificence of God's
creation seems to expand with every
passing [music] second, as if eternity
itself is constantly growing more
beautiful and captivating. At this
moment, I am speechless and humbled by
the power [music] and goodness of God.
I cannot fully comprehend how this is
possible, [music] but I am filled with
an overwhelming sense of anticipation.
Every step brings us closer to
fulfilling our ultimate destiny. And
eternity beckons us with its
unfathomable wonders.
With every passing moment, our capacity
to appreciate [music] the power of God
grows exponentially while at the same
time fainting at the sheer magnitude of
it.
The arrival. [music]
I am absolutely speechless. It is a
sight beyond comparison. As we approach
the vast majestic gates of the city of
God, our accompanying [music] angels
blow their trumpets, announcing our soon
arrival. Though we still have a full
day's journey, the city is already
visible in the distance. Its radiant
glory shining through the heavenly
skies, we are nearing heaven's shores.
With each passing moment, the
anticipation and awe within us only
intensify. A profound silence permeates
the atmosphere. It is a silence that
speaks volumes, for nothing I, we have
ever experienced before can compare to
the magnificence that now meets our
eyes. We who once dwelt on earth had
often read the description of heaven and
made countless attempts to visualize its
splendor. But what we now behold exceeds
every expectation. [music]
1 Corinthians 2:9. As we draw closer to
the celestial city, its grandeur becomes
increasingly [music] evident.
Its beauty surpasses anything the human
mind could conceive [music] or the human
heart could long for. Encircling the
city appear countless inhabitants from
faroff worlds, distant galaxies, and
parallel universes that dwarf the
massive number of our caravan. They have
come from every city and nation of God's
creation to celebrate the redemption of
humanity, the one lost sheep in God's
vast universe that has now been brought
home. Luke [music] 15:4.
This is to be our home where we will
spend a thousand years in perfect
communion with our Lord and Savior
[music] Jesus Christ. Revelation 24.
Before we return to make the earth our
permanent home. It is here that we will
walk alongside him basking in his
radiant presence [music] and
experiencing the fullness of his love. 2
Corinthians 6:16. Revelation 7:17.
For centuries since the fall of Adam,
the promise of the new Jerusalem has
burned brightly in the hearts of
believers. [music]
Countless faithful souls were laid to
rest with unwavering faith, patiently
awaiting the fulfillment of [music] this
promise. Now we stand in the very
presence of that long- awaited reality,
the New [music] Jerusalem, a city beyond
human comprehension. It is alive and
vibrant, [music] filled with
indescribable joy and unimaginable
splendor. Even the angels who have
witnessed [music] countless wonders and
glorious moments throughout eternity
cannot contain their excitement. [music]
They watch us with eager anticipation,
their eyes filled with delight, like a
parent eagerly awaiting their child's
unveiling of a life-changing [music]
gift. They too have yearned for this
moment, and they share in our joy and
astonishment as we [music] behold the
breathtaking beauty of the city of God.
Indeed, words [music] fail to capture
the overwhelming awe and wonder that
fills our hearts as we approach this
heavenly realm. [music]
It is a place of unimaginable peace,
love, and beauty. This is the
fulfillment of our deepest hopes and
[music] the realization of our wildest
dreams. A place where the redeemed will
dwell in eternal bliss, basking in the
glory of our creator. [music]
And as we approach those golden gates at
the city's entrance, we tremble with
joy. [music]
We are about to see the face of the
heavenly father and commune with the
lamb [music] of God which took away our
sins. Revelation 22 and:4. [music]
We are on our ascent into the city which
rests on a magnificent and exceedingly
high mountain. Revelation 21:10.
As we ascend, throngs of the sons of God
from every nation of the unfallen worlds
shout with joy. The city radiates a
brilliant light that emanates from the
father [music] himself. A light so
powerful that it would have destroyed
our previous earthly forms. However,
this light fills us with power, joy,
love, [music] and peace instead of
destruction, elevating our capacity to
experience these emotions. It is as if
we are being charged with happiness
itself. The wall of the city is higher
than our most extraordinary [music]
skyscrapers. I am at a loss of how to
describe the beauty of it. We see the 12
gates of pearls with the names of the 12
tribes written on them. [music] We are
arranged into 12 companies entering by
those 12 gates. Though we are a [music]
great multitude from every nation that
existed on earth, we enter through these
gates [music] because of the promise
given to Abraham. In giving our lives to
Christ, we became heirs of Abraham even
though many of us were not of his
bloodline.
Galatians [music] 3:26-29.
The entire city is gold. Unlike the gold
we remember on earth, this gold [music]
is crystal clear, solid, and
indestructible. I can now see why John
described the city the way he did. He
could not find adequate words. And now,
in my redeemed and glorified [music]
state, neither can I. The golden streets
are lined with, well, I don't know what
to call them [music] yet. But they are
beings from everywhere. Many different
colors, heights, and sizes, all as
unique in personality [music] as we were
on Earth. Now Jesus leads us to a sea of
glass mingled with fire before it.
[music] The Father is seated on a
flaming throne with wheels of fire.
Revelation 4: 6. [music]
Revelation 15:2,
Daniel 7, and 9. The fire flows out from
him onto the sea on which we stand. We
do not feel pain in that fire as we
would in the old flesh. Instead, we now
understand that fire is synonymous with
unspeakable love in this city. It is
what we felt in the resurrection. What
we felt from the fiery angels. [music]
What flowed into us when we saw Jesus
wrapped in flames. And now we understand
why the wicked could not be in heaven.
The eternal fire of God's presence. The
sea of glass mingled with fire. The
fiery angels and their chariots. All
representations of love in heaven would
be to them an eternal hell. Hebrews 12
29. Song of Solomon 8 6-8. Isaiah
[music] 33:es
14-16. Like the men who threw the three
Hebrews into the fire and were
destroyed, the wicked cannot stand in
heaven's presence in the unveiled
[music] glory of love. Here Jesus begins
to place a crown on each of our heads.
Revelation 2 and 10. Each of you are
here. He says, because you accepted by
faith my sacrifice on your behalf, you
have been justified by my blood. Romans
5:9
Romans 4:23-2
You are here not because [music] of your
works but because of your faith.
Galatians 2:16 But you have also kept my
commandments and therefore [music]
have right to the city and the tree of
life. Revelation 22:14
Revelation 14:12. [music]
You not only avoided the error of
trusting in the works of the law to save
you, but you also [music]
understood that faith without works was
not real faith. James 2 [music]
20 and 26. By keeping my commandments,
you avoided the works of the flesh,
adultery, [music] lawlessness, murder,
lying. Matthew 19 18, Romans 13:9,
Galatians 5:19. [music]
Many who professed to know me did not
keep my commandments, but used faith as
cover to live how they wanted. 1 John
2:4.
Not only did they do this themselves,
but they taught others that my law did
not matter. Matthew 5 19. I remember a
statement I read from the Methodist
preacher John Wesley that had moved me
with amazement that there were people
who professed to follow Christ yet at
the same time taught that his ten
commandments were no longer required to
be honored by believers. Wesley, who now
stands in the crowd among us, wrote, "In
the highest rank of the enemies of the
gospel of Christ, are they who openly
and explicitly judge the law itself, and
speak [music] evil of the law, who teach
men to break, to dissolve, to loose, to
untie the obligation of not one only,
whether of the least or of the [music]
greatest, but all the commandments at a
stroke." The most surprising of all the
circumstances [music] that attend this
strong delusion is that they who are
given up to it really believe that they
honor Christ by overthrowing his law
[music] and that they are magnifying his
office while they are destroying his
doctrine. Yay, they honor him just
[music] as Judas did when he said,
"Hail, master," and kissed him. And he
may as justly say to every one of them,
"Betray thou the son of man with a
kiss." [music] It is no other than
betraying him with a kiss, to talk of
his blood and take away his crown, to
set light by any part of his law under
pretense of advancing his gospel. Nor
indeed can anyone escape this charge who
preaches [music] faith in any such a
manner as either directly or indirectly
tends to set aside any branch [music] of
obedience.
Who preaches Christ so as to weaken in
any wise the least of the commandments
of God. John Wesley sermons page 264.
[music]
Jesus continues, "You are not here
because you kept my commandments
perfectly, but you demonstrated true
sorrow for your sins and desired and
strove to abide by my commandments
because of your love for me."
John 14:15.
Because you have acknowledged the laws
of my kingdom and allowed me to write
them on your hearts and minds. [music]
Hebrews 8 to10. I crown you as kings in
my universe. [music]
And then we are told something that
absolutely stuns us. We are told that we
will reign with Jesus for 1,000 [music]
years. It takes a moment to sink in.
Jesus reigns over every planet, every
interuniversal city and nation. [music]
And now he has just invited us to reign
with him. Revelation 1:6. Revelation
5:6. Revelation [music] 3 21. Revelation
20:6. we can hardly comprehend it. He is
going to allow [music] us to rule with
him over his vast territory. He is going
to let us see how he governs and in so
doing [music] we will better understand
the hows and wise of his operations on
earth. Feeling utterly unworthy, [music]
we cast our crowns at his feet. Moved
with emotion at the redemption and cost
of our salvation. Every mind wonders how
[music] we could have let the things of
the world sway us so much against
following after the Lord. The allure of
earthly pleasures [music] and the lusts
that once captivated and enslaved us now
seem entirely irrelevant and
inconsequential compared [music] to the
glory of the city of God. It is
incomprehensible to us how so many
people missed out on this [music]
eternal experience for temporary worldly
pursuits. If they could have only
imagined this, if they had but for
[music] a few hours closed their eyes
and allowed their imagination to grasp
the glory we now behold. How many of
those now lost would have gladly [music]
given up the world for the unspeakable
riches of heaven?
The promised supper that Christ had
foretold to his disciples is now taking
place. Luke 22 29 and 30, Matthew 8:11.
Tables are beautifully set, and to our
astonishment, Jesus himself serves us
just as he did when he walked the earth.
Luke 12:37,
John 13:4 and 5. This supper is a
commemoration and celebration of our
liberation and deliverance from the
world, similar to how the Israelites
were freed from Egypt. The food served
is indescribably exquisite, beyond
anything we have ever tasted before. It
is in fact, well, [music] out of this
world. What makes this truly special are
the conversations taking place around
the tables. We are privileged to listen
to testimony after testimony [music]
from individuals who had been saved from
their sins and had given their lives to
Christ. Revelation 12 [music]
11. Through these testimonies, we gain
insight into their stories, their
struggles, and their ultimate victory.
We are captivated [music] as we hear the
accounts of martyrs who remained
faithful to Christ in the face of
persecution and death. We listen to
Abraham, Isaac, and Jacob fill in
details not recorded in the Bible with
Sarah, Rebecca, Rachel, and Leah adding
to those accounts. There is an
atmosphere of joy and marrynt that fills
the air, serving as a soothing balm to
our hearts. Proverbs 17:22.
Angels and heavenly beings eagerly share
with us stories of the incredible worlds
and planets that Christ has created,
promising us that there is so much more
to see and experience. As the supper
draws to a close, we come to the
realization that eternity will not be
enough time to explore all the wonders
that lie before us. [music] Furthermore,
it becomes evident that it will take an
eternity to hear all the testimonies and
stories from the multitude of redeemed
[music] souls. During this time, we are
also shown the mansions where we will
reside throughout the thousand-year
reign. [music] While they unfold the
glories of heaven before our eyes, we
are also informed of the significant
work that lies ahead for us during
[music] this period. As kings, we have
been commissioned to review and judge
the cases of all the deceased who
[music] remain on the old earth,
including Satan and the bound angels. 1
Corinthians 6 1:3 [music]
Revelation 20:4
Ezekiel 28:17 [music]
We come to understand that at the end of
the thousand years we will return to
earth where Jesus will [music] relocate
the new Jerusalem the ultimate
fulfillment of the promise made to
Abraham
the earth will be recreated [music]
revelation 21 verse 1 but before this
the wicked who are currently dead on the
Earth will be resurrected to [music]
face their punishment. Revelation 20 5
and 6. Revelation 11 [music] and 12.
With the countless number of the wicked
dead throughout all the ages, it will
take us the entire thousand years to
[music] deliberate and pronounce
judgment on each individual, including
Satan and the fallen angels. The
proceedings will [music] be broadcasted
throughout the world as the redeemed
will observe in panoramic view the
rebellion of Lucifer in heaven and track
its effects [music] throughout the ages
of earth's history leading up to the
second coming of Christ. The wicked will
have [music] their day in court before
they are ultimately destroyed. As we
come to understand that our own loved
ones who did not choose to follow the
truth will also [music] be judged during
these proceedings. We begin to grasp the
significance of God's promise to wipe
away all tears from our eyes after the
thousand years, not before it.
Revelation 21:es 1-4.
We come to understand that at least for
a time there will be tears [music] in
heaven.
The courtroom. It is an incredibly
solemn and awe inspiring [music] moment.
The highly anticipated proceedings have
commenced and the divine courtroom is
filled to capacity with a multitude of
people and celestial beings. We are
informed [music]
that a momentous event, a judgment of
profound significance prior to the
glorious second coming of Christ
unfolded in these very courts [music] to
ascertain our salvation and our rightful
place in the celestial realm. [music]
Daniel 7 9 and 10. While the previous
judgments solely involved angels, this
time the redeemed have been graciously
invited into the Supreme Court [music]
of Heaven to actively participate in
this monumental trial. As heavenly
[music] jurors, we examine the cases of
all lost souls from all ages,
meticulously scrutinizing whether they
were granted equal [music] opportunities
for salvation and contemplating if any
additional measures could have been
undertaken to rescue them. These
questions involve our loved ones. They
are not asked lightly. [music]
Undoubtedly, the question that weighs
heavily upon our minds is whether God in
every instance did everything
conceivable short of coercion to save
each individual. Should we discover a
single case in which God did not exhaust
all possible measures, [music] thereby
validating Satan's claim of divine
injustice, it would be a staggering
revelation. The fact that the creator of
the universe willingly subjects himself
to the judgment of his creation is
nothing short of astounding. [music]
Psalms 51:4.
As members of the jury, we must
scrutinize each case with unparalleled
attention, as if there were not another
case under examination. The celestial
records afford us the privilege [music]
of perusing every individual's history,
penetrating the depths of their hearts,
rendering the need for any [music]
explanation superfluous as their
intentions become unequivocally clear.
[music] We embark on a captivating
journey, retracing the origins of the
first rebellion in heaven and [music]
tracing the foundational principles of
that conflict throughout the annals of
earthly history, culminating in the
glorious second advent of Christ.
[music] As participants in this divine
trial, we are granted the freedom to
question God himself, [music]
posing any inquiry our inquisitive minds
may conceive regarding his past dealings
with those under condemnation. [music]
In this judgment, every single redeemed
soul rests confidently in the absolute
certainty that God's ways and decisions
remain unimpeachable. His justice is
injubitable, and this unwavering
conviction pervades [music] our very
being. We comprehend the unprecedented
humility of our king who willingly
[music] permits his subjects to
scrutinize and validate his work. This
judgment serves as the definitive
resolution, eradicating any vestage of
uncertainty or doubt that might linger
in the minds of the redeemed, ensuring
that no future rebellion challenging the
goodness of God will ever transpire
again in the celestial abode. Nahom 1:9.
With this [music] the court adjourns.
While the solemn responsibility of this
[music] judgment rests deeply upon us,
we are eager to take up the invitations
of angels to explore worlds [music] and
universes. And this we do.
[music]
[music] A small group of us, 10,000 in
number, have taken a little time to go
on an expedition to a local planet that
hosts some of [music] the most vivid
marine life in this part of the
universe. The ability to fly is still
new to us and is absolutely [music]
exhilarating. Isaiah 40:31
that we can travel [music] great
distances in such short periods is so
thrilling. As we arrive on this awe
inspiring [music] planet, we witness
firsthand the breathtaking artistic
mastery of the creator. Every [music]
corner of this memerizing world pulsates
with a symphony of colors and shapes,
captivating our senses and igniting a
wildfire of amazement. The brilliance
[music] of the marine life that thrives
here is a testament to our divine makers
unfathomable [music] creativity. We
don't need swimming gear or machines to
explore underwater. This is just
amazing. [music]
I think to myself, and we never have to
die. I know [music] the thought just
pops out of nowhere, but every time it
happens, we are again overwhelmed with
joy. [music]
On this journey, I met several former
atheists who lived during the 19th and
20th [music] centuries and shared that
their conversions were due to the
prophecies of Daniel and Revelation.
They recalled that [music] they
understood that human beings did not
possess the power to accurately foretell
the future. And it was not until they
had [music] studied the prophecies of
Daniel and saw how it accurately
predicted the over 2500s years of
history by foretelling the rise and fall
of the ancient empires [music] of
Babylon, Meo Persia, Greece, and Rome.
and then went on to accurately predict
[music] the fall of Rome into various
smaller kingdoms and then the rise of
religious persecution out of the fallen
[music] Roman Empire. Even prophesying
the length of that persecution, that
they were convinced of the supernatural
nature of the book. They studied [music]
the prophecies in connection with
history and came to the inevitable
conclusion that they had to be divinely
inspired.
I [music] just nodded with a smile of
satisfaction as I had been aware of
these prophecies myself [music] and knew
the effect they could have if rightly
understood.
This quick trip was a [music] blessing
and the expedition breathtaking, but it
was now time to return to jury duty. We
have more questions and eagerly await
the answers. [music]
The first rebellion. A profound silence
fills the air in the courtroom, gripping
everyone with anticipation. We are about
to watch the unfolding of the mystery of
iniquity as it happened in real time.
[music] The entire universe is tuned in
to the trial. I lean forward in my seat
with my eyes locked onto the scene
before us, eager to understand how
Lucifer, a once perfect being in a
flawless heaven, could have gone astray.
Now I am about to understand. In this
scene, we are taken back to eternity
past, long before the 7-day creation of
Earth. I watch as the mighty power of
God, the Father, Son, and Holy Spirit,
creates Lucifer, [music]
the crowning work of angels. He is
dazzling, I think to myself, far [music]
surpassing our recollection of him when
we left him bound on earth. Every aspect
of Lucifer's character is flawlessly
perfect. Ezekiel [music] 28 12 and 13.
His musical prowess embodies the
celestial as he worships God with a
resounding and mighty song. Ezekiel
28:14.
He is full of love and joy. It is
strange to me to see him once happy,
[music] peaceful, and worshiping God.
The angels who were formed after him
[music] adore and honor him. He moves
throughout the universe as a special
messenger of the Godhead, basking in a
likeness and beauty [music] that mirrors
God himself. Lucifer is a covering
cherub, a role [music] attributed only
to the highest ranking angels closest to
God's throne. The covering cherubim were
the two angels that stood closest
[music] to the throne of God. This was
illustrated in the Hebrew sanctuary
where the mercy seat, the symbol of
God's throne, was flanked by two angels
[music] who had their wings spread out
covering the ark of the covenant, which
contained the commandments of God.
[music] Exodus 25:10 to22. The mercy
seat rested on top of the ark of the
covenant, symbolizing that God's throne
in heaven, the seat of his [music]
government, was founded on his law.
Lucifer's job description was to show
the holiness of and reverence for the
law of God and the throne of heaven.
[music] But then sin was found in him.
Sin is the transgression of the law.
First John [music] 3:4. The revelation
comes to many of us that the rebellion
in heaven [music] began over Lucifer
casting doubt on the necessity of
heavenly beings needing to obey the law.
We watch [music] as Lucifer began to
claim that he was like God in holiness
while at the same time disregarding the
law as obsolete. Isaiah 14 [music]
12-4. We watch as Lucifer proposed that
angels were holy and did not need a law
to govern them. We watch the argument
catch on until a full one-third [music]
of the angels, the stars of heaven,
bought into his lie. Revelation [music]
12. This, we begin to understand, was
the origin and root of all wickedness.
[music] Lucifer's self-righteousness.
Because of this attack against God's
law, heaven, which had [music] been a
place of rest, became a place of war.
Hebrews 4:1,
Revelation 12:7. [music] Satan had
broken this state of rest. As a result,
he was cast out of heaven and his angels
[music] with him. Revelation 12:8. As we
observe this scene, the origin and
essence of the idea that plagued planet
[music] Earth becomes evident. The
concept of self-righteousness, the
belief that one can be inherently good
without God or without his law, leading
individuals to determine their own moral
compass between right and wrong, was of
satanic origin. This satanic principle
had even been embraced by many
professing the name of Christ. 1 John
2:4. Days and months of testimony come
before the court as countless angels who
fought in the war offer their firsthand
accounts of events leading up to the
rebellion. We become privy to the
ceaseless appeals made to Lucifer and
his cohorts, urging them to repent and
renounce their rebellious ways. Matthew
18 21 and 22.
Lucifer intended to establish his own
government [music] where personal
desires would reign supreme and he would
be worshiped as God. Only after every
opportunity for repentance [music] had
been exhausted was the measure of war
initiated. The war in heaven resulted in
[music] Satan and his followers being
banished to Tardaroo, also known as
planet earth before God's creative
[music] work began on it. 2 Peter 2:4
Revelation 12:8. [music]
The newly crowned kings question amongst
ourselves with curiosity. [music] Why
earth? An angel redirects our thoughts
to an instruction given by God to Moses
[music] during his life on earth as the
leader entrusted with governing the
children of Israel. We are reminded that
a jury or a third party was to be formed
in disputes between [music] two
individuals or parties to ensure an
impartial judgment. Neither the accused
nor the accuser could sit as the judge
as it would compromise the integrity of
the trial. We are then reminded that in
the war in heaven there were two
opposing [music] factions. There was no
third party, no jury in the ultimate
outcome of this controversy. It dawns on
[music] us that part of the reason God
created humanity on earth in the very
place that Satan was originally cast out
was to serve as his jurors. We are the
kings, [music]
the third party that would judge
Lucifer.
Ezekiel 28:17
1 Corinthians [music] 6:1-3.
Understanding that jurors must be
law-abiding citizens who know the
difference between right and wrong and
must not have had contact [music] with
the original crime, we now understand
Satan's hatred for humanity. The
intensity of Satan's war against us
while on [music] earth and his
relentless pursuit to lead us into sin
is now clear. If he could [music] have
successfully subjected humanity under
his control, he would have eliminated
the jury and subsequently the
possibility of his own condemnation.
[music]
If he could prove the jurors unworthy of
serving because of their own
transgressions and disregard of God's
law, they would effectively [music] be
eliminated from jury duty. With this
bombshell revelation, as the courtroom
[music] adjourns, a sense of awe and
gravity permeates the atmosphere.
Today I spent most of my time with my
guardian angel who was assigned to me on
earth. During our impromptu tour of the
new Jerusalem, [music] our conversation
had me captivated as he told me of how
often he had saved me from the grips of
danger and death. I could not have
imagined how much God's love for me had
been exercised in the preservation of my
life. I remembered the time I had been
working under my car, which [music] was
mounted on a car jack. The phone rang.
It was my sister, but I did not answer
it in time. [music]
Thinking the call was urgent, I rolled
out from under the car and stood up to
return the call when, without warning,
the vehicle fell off the jack. [music]
In shock, I called my sister back to
tell her that her call saved my life.
However, when I got [music] her, she
told me she had made no such call. This
left us both shocked and puzzled.
regarding the day I went to church for
the [music] first time. He told me that
the spirit had been drawing me to
respond to the invitation and
orchestrated a series of events that
gave me [music] the greatest likelihood
of accepting it. He told me that I had
the freedom to reject the invitation,
[music]
but did not because of the influence of
several of my friends that had been used
to reflect the goodness of God to me. My
angel told [music] me how daily various
salvation cues had been planted in my
path, leading me step by step from a
rebellious child to my finally [music]
embracing the cross. I was amazed.
Little things like my next [music] door
neighbor's kind words to me when I
accidentally broke his window with my
ball to observing my high school teacher
reading his Bible during break times. A
[music] symphony of events had been
orchestrated, not to control my destiny,
but [music] to create the best possible
condition for me to accept the gospel.
Even [music] the complex trials I had
experienced had been carefully measured
and weighed by God so that it would not
be more than I could handle. 1 [music]
Corinthians 10:3. But what about others
who suffered death, who didn't have a
chance to [music] know Christ? I asked.
What about those who died young, died in
accidents, or those children who were
abused, or suffered hunger and famine?
[music]
Those who suffered hardship in life and
looked for God in their lives and did
not see him working on their behalf.
Where were their guardian angels? I ask
[music] earnestly. He explained,
"Suffering on earth is not a sign that
God has forsaken anyone." [music] He
points to the light of the lamb
radiating the city. Revelation 21 23.
Remember he says the son of God suffered
famine, abuse, rejection and death. And
yet he was the beloved father of his
father.
>> Christ's death on the cross proved that
suffering is not synonymous with
disapproval from God. He then asks me,
"How many of the redeemed have you met
here that appeared to [music] be cursed
with calamity on earth?"
>> "Yes, I know." I said, "I've [music]
lost count." "Exactly," he replied.
Remember, he then says, [music] and I
finish his sentence, the parable of
Lazarus and the rich man. Though this
story given by Christ was just a
parable, it illustrated the truth that
those who suffered on earth were not to
[music] be viewed as being automatically
cursed or forsaken by God. In a sin-ick
world where sin by nature plays by no
rules, the righteous [music] can suffer
and the wicked can prosper. Jeremiah 5
28 Jeremiah 12:1
The conversation gives me greater
clarity on some nagging questions I
could not answer while I was alive on
the old earth. [music] After some time
we head to the center of the city where
the court is about to be seated again.
It is going to be another spectacular
hearing.
I had been eagerly awaiting this day. We
are about to watch in hind vision one of
the most [music] significant events in
human history. the creation of the earth
of our first parents and their
consequential [music]
fall in the Garden of Eden. The scene
unfolds and what so many of us had read
and imagined a thousand [music] times
over is now happening before our eyes as
if we were there. We see the darkness
upon the face of the deep and the spirit
moving, hovering [music] over the
waters. We watch as God says, "Let there
be light." And a blast of energy
suddenly envelops the abyss [music]
where Satan had been cast. Revelation
12:9.
And then we behold as God begins to
create the earth. Our eyes, our eyes
can't believe [music] what we are
seeing. The earth as it came forth from
the hand of God is so unlike what we had
grown [music] accustomed to. An earth
under the curse and darkness of sin. The
trees, the grass, [music] a green so
vivid and deep, unlike anything we were
used to. The brightness of the sky,
every part of the earth in its original
glory has us stunned into silence. After
we view the successive days of creation,
we watch our first parents formation.
Then [music] we see God sanctifying the
seventh day, the Sabbath, the symbol of
rest. [music]
At that moment, the spirit whose work it
is to bring things to our memory
highlights in every king's mind that the
Sabbath was given to [music] keep humans
from the error of Satan who thought that
he could sanctify himself. Ezekiel
20:12. The Sabbath was the sign that God
is the sanctifier, not we ourselves.
[music] It was given as a sign to earth
that it was in harmony with the state of
rest in heaven. As long as Adam and Eve
stayed faithful to God, the world would
also be in a state of rest regardless of
Satan's presence, he could have no power
over them except that they [music] give
it to him. As we continue watching, we
see God creating the tree of life and
the tree of the knowledge of good and
evil. [music] A tree which if eaten by
Adam and Eve would lead to sin and
death.
Among the redeemed in heaven, [music]
there is a mixed multitude. Some have
excellent knowledge of the Bible and its
contents while others have little or no
knowledge of it. And in many [music]
cases, some have inaccurate or faulty
knowledge. So with patience, the [music]
court answers questions ranging from
simple to complex. At this point, a
question is raised. [music]
Why was the tree of the knowledge of
good and evil placed in the garden,
especially if [music] eating it would
lead to death? An angel answers that man
could have either been made with the
freedom to choose or made as mere
automated beings explicitly [music]
doing the will of God without choice. If
made as automations, they would not have
the capacity to [music] love because
love requires the freedom to choose.
Love cannot be programmed. In prior
creations, [music]
evil did not exist. The freedom to
choose was not a choice between [music]
good and evil, but between good and
good. But since Satan's rebellion, evil
had now entered the universe. Freedom of
choice now meant [music] between good
and evil. If God was to proceed with the
creation of man as beings [music]
capable of love, this was the risk. God
chose to give man the freedom of choice
and used himself as the guarantee that
even if man [music] decided to do evil,
he would be offered a path back to
eternal life through the death of God
himself. Again, the kings are in awe
that God [music] would give his life to
redeem fallen men. The test given to man
was a simple one, obedience [music] to
the word of the creator. It is an
indescribable moment as we watch Eve,
then Adam yield to the temptation to eat
from the forbidden tree. We now
understand why God does not intervene to
stop them. We watch as the heart of God
is broken. In [music] yielding to Satan,
the rest on earth, signified by the
Sabbath, [music] had been broken, and
this planet became the battlefield
between good and evil. [music] The
creation was no longer good. Genesis
2:es 1:3. In essence, Satan had [music]
bribed the jury. It dawns upon us that
what at first appears to be a trivial
test is really the revealing of Satan's
working of iniquity. [music] He had
tempted Adam and Eve with the same lie
he used in heaven. That they could be
holy like God without obeying his word.
[music] They could determine good and
evil for themselves. This principle,
this contest would [music] play out over
and over in human history, culminating
with a final deception so deeply laid
that by the end of human history,
[music]
the leading proponents of this theory
would be professed Christians who would
[music] ultimately wage a final
rebellion precisely like the one waged
by Lucifer and his angels in heaven.
[music] John 16:2.
We watch Jesus walk into the garden
looking for Adam and Eve. We watch as
they hide in shame and are reminded of
the shame we once felt on earth. I
remember hiding from God [music] because
of my sins. At times trying to deny his
existence because the [music]
implication was that if he did exist, I
would most certainly be condemned.
Watching the scene unfold moves us with
holy [music] regret for our own former
sinfulness.
Yet since Adam and Eve acknowledge their
wrong, Genesis [music] 3:11-13,
they are given grace. An animal is slain
[music] to cover their nakedness. In
that sacrifice was the promise of the
coming deliverer, the lamb of [music]
God, slain from the foundation of the
world, who would through mercy restore
every repentant man and woman to [music]
being law-abiding citizens of the
kingdom of heaven and ultimately restore
them to their position of jurors.
[music]
God would seek to win mankind back
through the ultimate act of love. We are
here now because of the love of the lamb
who gave himself to cover us in his
righteousness. [music] Overcome with
emotion, we kings cast our crowns at the
feet of Jesus. And the court is
adjourned as we shout, "Holy, holy,
holy."
The next few court sessions are full of
massive revelations. [music] Part of our
work as jurors is to ascertain whether
every effort was made to save lost
people. What we learn as we review God's
interaction with those who did not make
it into the kingdom of heaven [music]
leads us to a greater understanding of
the true nature of sin, how it leads to
condemnation, and [music] most of all,
how God intervenes to give opportunity
to the wicked to escape death without
forcing them to choose [music] life.
First we watch the judgment which
culminated in the flood. We see that the
whole world has become wicked beyond
imagination. [music] Genesis 6:es 5 and
6. Only Noah is found righteous among
the [music] people. Yet unlike the
character of a brutal dictator, we see
that God provides [music] an ark, a way
of escape. 1 Corinthians 10:13.
that whosoever [music] chooses to escape
condemnation, believe his word, choose
to repent, and choose to take the way of
escape provided by God would live.
[music] No questions asked. No test to
get on the ark. That's simple. [music]
Just get on. Amazing. We think to
ourselves that sin actually led the
people to choose death rather than
[music] life, to choose to ignore the
warning, rather than prepare and accept
the alternative to live. We now
understand from the flood account that
all who are ultimately lost chose
[music] death over life. As an arc of
safety was presented for those willing
to live. Jesus's sacrifice on behalf of
all men was the way of escape [music]
for all who would take it. Not one
person needed to be lost. Not one. We
[music] then proceed to the judgment of
Sodom and Gomorrah. Again, we find these
cities were full of [music] wickedness.
And again, God is willing to spare the
city. to spare the wicked if only a
handful of righteous [music] people can
be found. Genesis 18:es 20 to33.
The character of God once again is
demonstrated [music] to be
long-suffering, not willing that any
should perish, but that all should come
to repentance. It is also revealed how
blinding sin is. The people of the city
attempted to assault Lot, Abraham's
nephew, and the two angels disguised as
men who went to investigate the city's
wickedness. Genesis 19:es 1:5. The men
attempted to break into Lot's house
where the two angels were. In response,
the angels blinded them, a supernatural
act that should have alerted the city's
men that this was God's hand. Instead,
they were so blinded by sin and bent on
evil, that they still sought the door of
the house to assault the angels instead
of repenting or even so much as being
concerned about losing their eyesight.
Genesis 19 11.
We continue to behold as the scene goes
to the judgment during the Exodus. We
watch as God brings plague after plague
upon Egypt. Back on earth, this was a
point that was often dwelt on by enemies
of God in an attempt [music] to show God
as a relentless bully. However, we see
that even here, after [music] every
plague poured out upon Egypt, God would
answer the prayers of Pharaoh to take
away the plagues. Exodus 8:8, [music]
Exodus 8 29, Exodus 9:28.
What tyrant answers his enemy's prayer
for [music] mercy? And despite this
continued extension of grace, many
Egyptians rejected God. We conclude
[music] that God's long-suffering and
mercy were extended to every lost human
being, just as to Pharaoh and the
Egyptians. [music] And the mercy was not
in vain, for it was a mixed multitude
that left Egypt. God allowed [music] the
Egyptians, the oppressors of his people
who repented and decided to trust God to
come to be a part of his people. Exodus
12:38, [music]
48, and 49.
One of the most explosive revelations
comes regarding God's dealing with the
nations occupying Canaan's land. [music]
He had commanded these nations to be
removed
on earth. This was perhaps [music] the
most extraordinary accusation against
God, that he was guilty of genocide.
Many of us as Christian believers on
earth did not know how [music] to deal
with this question when brought up by
opponents of the Bible. And as for the
kings who had not known Christ [music]
by name while on earth, they too are
eager to understand God's work here.
[music] Again, what we learn align with
what we have seen in the previous
judgments of the flood, Sodom and
Gomorrah, [music] and the Exodus.
One of the angels of the court explains
that these nations were under
condemnation [music] for the same
reasons that brought about the flood.
Namely, that these nations had practiced
extreme wickedness. Leviticus 18. Still,
[music] we learn that the Bible writers
did not and could not have recorded all
the details of every single event in the
scriptures. The records in heaven have
every detail needed to fully understand
the [music] case. And now we know why
God required us to exercise faith that
is trust in God. As we look at [music]
these sealed documents and get the whole
picture, we are again brought to the
justness of God. Still, [music] the
Bible contained enough information on
this issue to understand God's justice.
God told Israel he would send hornets
among these nations to drive them out.
No battle [music] necessary. Thus, only
the most stubborn, rebellious, and
hard-hearted remained behind by the time
Israel had gotten [music] to that city.
Deuteronomy 7 20. Even then, Israel was
to first declare peace upon the [music]
city to give them a chance to surrender
without war. If they agreed to peace,
they were to serve Israel as
tributaries. Deuteronomy 20:es [music]
10 and 11. This was God's method of
humbling that city, allowing them to
submit to a lesser punishment and
ultimately come back in line with him as
tributaries. [music]
They were not to be treated unjustly. If
a servant was physically assaulted so
that he lost so much as a [music] tooth,
he was to be set free. Exodus 21 26 and
27. We are reminded that God exercised
the same punishment [music] towards
rebellious Israel who began committing
the same wickedness as the nations
before them in the land. As a result,
the nation of Babylon removed them from
their own [music] land. They were given
the opportunity to submit to God's
punishment by becoming tributaries to
Babylon. They refused [music] and their
city was destroyed. 2 Kings 25 24.
God [music] was extending a last chance
of mercy to these nations. If the
nations refused, [music] God would move
to the next step, which was that all the
men of the city were to die for their
sins, but the women and children were
allowed to live. Deuteronomy [music] 20
and:14.
However, there was an exception
regarding seven specific [music] cities.
These seven cities were to be destroyed,
man, woman, and child. Deuteronomy
20:17, [music]
we learn that these seven nations
practiced biological wickedness. These
were nations that practiced incest, not
sporadically, [music] but generation
after generation until the mental,
spiritual, physical, and moral [music]
deformities within these cities because
of their rebellion against God left no
other course. Societies [music] and
families that practiced inbreeding could
expect their children to live with the
most destructive diseases and die early
deaths.
These seven cities were not full of
people [music] seeking healing, but were
full of the rebellious and those intent
on continuing their course of action.
God or no God. Leviticus [music]
18 6 to2.
All that still remained in these cities
after [music] the hornets were beyond
the possibility of redemption.
With these judgments [music]
in front of us, and as we begin to
behold the records of the lost, the
truths we have just learned bear out.
[music]
Example after example is provided that
the lost of every age had been granted
mercy time after time and yet rejected
it. For they had been so blinded [music]
by sin that despite God's manifestations
of grace, they persevered in evil or had
become so engrossed in sin that they
were hopelessly deformed spiritually,
emotionally, and morally. These had
rejected the law of God which was to
[music] be the very standard of the
judgment. Ecclesiastes 12
to4. With this knowledge, we begin the
work of reviewing the lives of the lost,
a work [music] no one in heaven takes
pleasure in.
Every Sabbath has been marked by our
[music] collective worship of the Lord
since our arrival. Isaiah 66:es [music]
22 and 23. I, as well as a great number
of the redeemed, celebrated our very
first Sabbath [music] within the walls
of the New Jerusalem. On earth, many of
us had faithfully yet erroneously
observed Sunday as the day of worship
under the mistaken [music] belief that
this was ordained by the Lord or his
apostles, a misconception propagated by
early church leaders. [music] It becomes
evident during the tribunal processes
that alterations to God's law were
maliciously [music] made, stemming from
Satan's rebellion against God's divine
statutes. Daniel 7 25. Moreover, [music]
some were misinformed about the
relevance of the Sabbath, believing it
to have been enulled or deemed
non-essential [music] for Gentile
believers. We were unaware that the
Gentiles observance of the Sabbath under
the new covenant [music] was explicitly
prophesied. Isaiah 56:es
1-8. Such knowledge would have
undeniably led us to embrace the [music]
Sabbath wholeheartedly. In our genuine
ignorance, God accepted our faith. Acts
[music] 17:30.
On the other hand, individuals who
professed to follow Christ, even
performing miracles, yet consciously
[music] chose to ignore his
commandments, revealed a disingenuous
aspect of their faith, preferring
tradition over the [music] authenticity
of divine command. Matthew 15:9, Matthew
7 21-23. [music]
Their actions rather than words
reflected their true spirit. Matthew 7
15 to 20. These are missing [music] from
heaven. Looking across the multitude in
the worship, I am greeted by familiar
faces, each with a [music] story I've
grown to know over several centuries.
This gathering includes former
Catholics, Baptists, Methodists, [music]
Presbyterians, and members from a wide
array of denominations. Through our
interactions, [music] it became clear
that judgment in the afterlife was not
rooted in denominational affiliations,
[music] but rather in the individuals
response to the light of truth they
received and lived by. [music]
The truly righteous were those who chose
truth over denominational ties,
embracing [music] new enlightenment
regardless of the cost. It wasn't the
quantity of light they had, but what
they did with it. Here we exist as a
unified [music] body, not divided by
differing beliefs, denominations.
Unified in vision, our hymns reverberate
throughout the New Jerusalem with
[music] a resonance that transcends our
past earthly experiences. Isaiah 51:1.
Each worship [music] session immerses us
in overwhelming peace, awe, and divine
love. Our weekly journeys [music] to
various planets culminate in our return
to New Jerusalem for worship, where we
delve into profound truths about
salvation, Christ's sacrifice, and the
battle between righteousness and [music]
evil. These services expand our
understanding of God's nature, aiding us
in our [music] roles within the
millennial judgment process.
In these moments of worship, we engage
[music] directly with Jesus, posing
inquiries about the intricacies of
redemption and biblical narratives that
once perplexed us. Prayer, as we knew
it, [music] is unnecessary here.
Instead, we converse directly with God,
asking challenging questions and most
importantly, [music]
experiencing the full intensity of his
love. Every worship session surpasses
the previous, continuously [music]
exceeding what we considered possible.
Yet it occurs repeatedly. This
experience [music] is exhilarating. It
is pure fire and we love it. [music]
Today, as we head [music] toward the
court, a solemn feeling is in the air.
Not oppressive, but heavy. The angels do
not speak. They seem emotional. a
strange mixture of sadness, pride, and
honor in each face. This causes us to
wonder what the revelations in today's
court [music] proceedings hold. And then
we behold a scene. It is not any scene
of Earth's history. [music] It is not
any scene regarding Lucifer's fall, nor
any scene of what is yet to come. What
we see is occurring in heaven. In this
very city, there is a massive crowd of
angels. They are surrounding the second
person of the Godhead. The Father and
Spirit are present.
>> [music]
>> We see angels with sorrowful looks. And
then we realize we are watching the
moment he, the second person of [music]
the Godhead, is saying goodbye to
heaven. The moment he is leaving to
become Jesus, the baby that will be born
in Bethlehem. They know his mission. It
[music] is to die for the sins of the
world. In vain, angels offer their own
lives as a sacrifice [music] instead of
him whom their souls loved. He tells
them that only a divine life will
suffice [music] to amend the breaking of
a divine law. Without the shedding of
blood, there can be no [music] remission
of sins. For man to live again, God must
die to satisfy his law. The scene
[music] brings a well of emotion to us
kings. We see now the glory Jesus left
to come and save us. We see the
friendships he leaves behind. We see not
only that he loved us but [music] that
every angel in heaven filled with that
same love for us would have gladly given
their lives to save us. It is a moment
that overwhelms [music] every one of us.
Tears flow silently. We watch father,
son, and spirit embrace. We now
understand the [music] looks on the
faces of the angels. Joy that we will be
redeemed. Sadness at the cost of that
redemption. The blood of their
commander. And then [music] he is gone.
Just like that, he will become a tiny
embryo. And for 9 months, he will grow
as every other child in a woman's womb.
He will be born flesh of [music] our
flesh and bone of our bone.
He will grow like every other child and
dwell among us. He [music] will
experience the trials and temptations
that every human faces and will overcome
them not in his own power, but in the
strength of his father. He will become
the pattern, the example of what man
[music] could do, not in his own power,
but when depending on the heavenly
father.
He will face the very angel his own hand
created.
He will face him not as God, but as man.
He will come to challenge Satan's claim
on the earth. He will come to fight for
us on our behalf. He will demonstrate
the power of his father. And then he
will do something spectacular. He will
take the sins of the entire world upon
himself. [music] And bearing those sins,
he will take them to the grave. The
second person of the Godhead will become
a man so that he can die for the world,
the whole world, the sinner from every
part of the globe. This that they might
be redeemed from the tyranny of the
enemy. The angels are instructed that
they cannot intervene to save him from
this death. Despite their desire, he
drinks from this cup alone. And in this
[music] moment, he will feel the sense
of his father's presence withdraw from
him. He knows this information in his
pre-incarnate state, but will not know
it when he becomes human. [music] He is
not pretending when he cries out, "My
God, my God, why hast thou forsaken me?"
It comes to him as a surprise that he
should be [music] forsaken by his
father. He will be tested in this
darkness to see if he will go through
with the sacrifice. If he is forsaken
[music] of his father and dies with the
sins of the world, he may not return to
the father, but instead come up with the
wicked in the second resurrection. And
yet, despite the [music] devil's
temptation with these thoughts, we see
Jesus close his eyes and yield up the
ghost, fully trusting [music] his
father. He did all this, not only for
the whole world, but also if only one
person was willing to accept his act of
love. And why this? Because only [music]
by love could love be awakened in the
hearts of rebellious mankind. And no
greater love could be demonstrated by
God than that he would lay his life down
for his friends. But God is the God of
impossibilities.
Because he did [music] not lay his life
down for his friends. He laid it down
for his enemies. Those who nailed him to
the cross. Those who [music] despised
and rejected him. He died for them. For
the wicked, for every soul who now lay
dead upon the desolate earth. [music] He
died for them. We do not know how, but
we can sense the emotional pain of the
father, son, [music] and spirit that so
great a sacrifice and mission to save so
many have been freely rejected by so
many. [music] God will honor the freedom
to choose at all costs. Even if it means
choosing death over life, the scene has
moved our hearts like nothing has ever
moved us in all our years upon the old
earth, watching the creative powers of
God and the majestic beauty of heaven.
Nothing compares to this scene [music]
of Christ's condescension, humiliation,
and death driven by his love for us.
[music] As we watch this scene, we are
paralyzed by love. When Jesus said to
his capttors in Gethsemane, "Do you not
think that I could not now call 12
legions of angel?" We watch as angels at
that moment were ready to move [music]
into formation to deliver Jesus. Still,
their hopes were dashed when he
continued that he must accomplish the
mission he came to do. We watch as
angels hide their faces from the abuse
Christ [music] suffered. We watch the
suffering of angels, of the father, of
the spirit while Christ suffers on the
cross and then dies.
[music] We watch as for 3 days Christ
lays in the grave taking on the curse.
First pronounced [music] to Adam that he
would return to the dust of the earth.
Genesis 3 19. And then early Sunday
morning, [music]
we watch a legion of angels speeding
toward the earth. [music] Even in our
glorified state, we are shocked at their
record speed.
The force with which this [music] legion
hits the earth causes an earthquake.
With violence, these angels put death on
notice. Jesus of his own power raises
[music] himself from the grave. Oh
death, where is thy victory? Oh grave,
where is thy sting? A roar of triumph
erupts [music] across the realms of all
God's creation. Jesus has defeated death
on behalf of humanity. As their [music]
representative, he opened the gates of
the grave that all who go into it may,
if they choose, [music] come out of it
again at his second coming. 40 days
later, Jesus, escorted by a heavenly
guard, [music] enters heaven.
The angels escorting Jesus shout as they
approach the gates of the city. Lift up
your heads gates [music]
and be lifted up from everlasting doors
and the king of glory shall come in. Who
is this king of glory? Responds the
celestial beings from other [music]
worlds triumphantly.
The angels reply, the Lord strong and
mighty, the Lord mighty in battle. Lift
up your heads, oh ye gates, even lift
them up, ye everlasting doors, and the
king of glory shall come in. Who is this
king of glory? [music] Jehovah of hosts.
He is the king of glory. Sailor.
Some friends and I are visiting the
Temple of Heaven today. Though I've been
here a thousand times before, every time
I enter, I feel like I am seeing it for
the first time. It takes our breath
away, not because of its beauty or
magnificence. [music] Yes, it far
exceeds anything we have ever seen on
earth. The walls glisten with gold.
[music] Seven shining golden lampstands
tower within its glorious precincts. The
flames, these seven spirits before the
throne of God, burn eternally, never
dimming, but glowing brighter and
brighter every moment. How this is
possible we do not understand. [music]
But it is mesmerizing to behold. Every
aspect of the temple reflects pure
perfection. But that is not what holds
us spellbound. [music] It is the
significance of the temple. After
leading the children of Israel out of
Egypt, God showed Moses a vision of this
very temple and then instructed him to
make a replica of it. This was the
blueprint from [music] which the Hebrew
sanctuary was made. Exodus 25 89 and 40.
Hebrews 8:1 and2.
The earthly model was a miniature
depiction of God's government in heaven
and was designed to reveal the character
of God and the principles of [music] the
gospel. Psalm 77:13.
Standing in this sanctuary, we see at a
glance the principles [music] of
salvation in each piece of holy
furniture. The seven burning lamps
symbolize that heaven's occupants are
beings of light and [music] truth. Just
as in the earthly sanctuary, the seven
branched candlestick was to teach the
lesson that God's people [music] had
been called to be the light of the
world, the city set on a hill.
Revelation 4:5, Matthew [music] 5:14-16.
As we behold the altar of incense, a
sense of overwhelming gratitude floods
through my soul. [music]
This was the very altar where our
prayers ascended, where Jesus, our high
priest, had interceded for us [music]
throughout all our trials and challenges
while we were living on earth.
Revelation 8:es 2 and [music] 3. This is
a surreal moment, I think to myself,
running my hand over the smooth [music]
edifice of the altar. Looking at my
reflection, I think to myself, I would
not be here [music] right now were it
not for grace. As we approach the golden
table, the same one that had been
promised to us where we would eat with
Abraham, Isaac, and Jacob, we reflect
[music] on the goodness of God in
raining heavenly mana down upon us to
guide us into all truth during our
earthly journey. This table symbolized
[music] by the table of showbread in the
Old Testament sanctuary is where we now
fellowship and gain a greater
understanding of the word of God. Luke
22:30, [music] Exodus 25:30.
On earth, the Bible was our bread. But
here, there is much more truth than the
Bible was able to contain. Stepping onto
the sea of glass mingled with fire
reminds us of the labor in the earthly
temple. [music] That basin of water
which was used to wash the hands and
feet of the priests. Revelation 4:6.
Exodus 30:18. [music] It was a symbol of
baptism representing new birth. Acts
1:5. Every time we stand on that sea of
glass, we are reminded of our new birth
spiritually at our [music] baptism and
literally when Christ came the second
time. As we behold the throne of God, we
are reminded of why it was referred to
as the mercy seat in the most holy place
of the [music] sanctuary. Revelation 4
1:3 Exodus 25:17 and 18. [music] We are
here only because of God's mercy and
thus it was also known as the throne of
grace. Hebrews 4:16. [music]
But the throne rested on top a special
foundation of gold. This was the ark of
the covenant. Revelation 11:19. This ark
[music] contained the law of God and was
proof that the law of God was the
foundation of God's government and
throne. Those who claimed God's mercy
[music] yet rejected his law did not
understand that to reject one part of
the throne was to reject all of it. Law
and mercy blend together. He extends
mercy [music] to those who keep his
commandments. Exodus 20:6. And every
time we behold Jesus, we are reminded
that he is the lamb that took away our
sins [music] on earth. The altar of
sacrifice pointed to this great truth.
And we are always reminded and grateful
that [music] this is the reason why we
are here. Revelation 5:6, Leviticus
[music] 3:5, John 1:29.
God had given the Old Testament
tabernacle as a blueprint, [music]
an object lesson of salvation. The plan
was simple. Jesus, the lamb, would come
to the world to die for [music] our sin,
represented by the altar of sacrifice.
His death would open the way for man to
be born again and washed from [music]
their sin, represented by the labor. The
born again Christian would eat the word
of God, pray continually, and let his
light shine as represented by the table
of showbread, [music] the altar of
incense, and the seven branched
candlestick. Those who were [music]
genuinely converted would find mercy at
the throne of grace and because of their
love for Christ would live lives in
harmony with his [music] law. Many
professed Christians accepted some of
these truths but openly rejected others
whether it was rejecting [music] the law
of God or refusing to let their light
shine. But in rejecting any of these
articles of furniture, they were
rejecting the plan [music] of salvation.
As we tour the temple, we are often
reminded of the lost who rejected in
part [music] or hold the blueprint of
salvation, yet are overwhelmed with joy
that an innumerable number heeded the
blueprint and are here. [music]
When Jesus knocks on my door, I am
always filled with awe and wonder. I
love it when he comes by, sits with me,
and eats with me.
>> Is that even possible? It feels like
each time we break bread together, my
life is forever changed in a way that I
will never forget.
Each conversation I have with him
enriches my understanding and [music]
deepens my love for him.
I once held the belief that heaven was a
place where we automatically knew
everything and questions would be a
thing of the past. In my assumption,
[music] I could not have been more
wrong. We are continuously engaged in
learning here just as we learned in our
earthly experiences. [music]
In this life, learning is immensely
rewarding. [music] There are no hard
lessons, no school of trial. These are
the moments I cherish most with him. He
leads me along the path of righteousness
[music] just as he did on earth,
enlightening and guiding me. And so, no
matter where you are, there I will
always [music]
>> The way in which righteousness functions
here is very different from how it
operated on earth. However, almost as if
through [music] a distant fog, we recall
the turmoil, pain, and destruction that
sin brought upon the earth throughout
[music] history. Armed with such
memories, the redeemed throughout
eternity choose never to [music] commit
sin again. Temptation, as we knew it on
Earth, is non-existent here. [music]
As Earth's gravitational pole lost its
hold on us at the resurrection, the
allure of temptation has also lost its
power over us. No one misses the tug of
sin now that it has ceased [music] to
exist.
Today I had a burning question on my
mind for Jesus. [music]
It was about the Bible study he had with
the disciples on the road to Emmas. The
Bible did not reveal the contents. It
only recorded that after that event, the
disciples hearts were set on fire.
Heartburn, they called it. Luke
24:13-32.
I had always wondered [music] what Jesus
said to those two disciples during the
study. And now was my chance to ask. And
as he shared with me the details of that
study, my heart quite literally felt the
burn. How I love that burn. It [music]
is a feeling unlike any other.
Reflecting on the former pleasures of
earth, none of them, whether pure or
unholy, could compare to the feeling of
the constant burn, the redeemed
experience [music] here. It isn't like a
fleeting high that diminishes and needs
to be relentlessly pursued and
replenished. No, here we are capable of
experiencing [music] the pinnacle of
this feeling continuously without
fatigue or exhaustion. Now with our
enhanced mental and emotional
capacities, [music] we are able to delve
into deeper truths that were beyond our
ability to grasp while we were on earth.
The spiritual nourishment [music] we
received on earth, the Bible, God's mana
from heaven, was just mere fragments,
small enough pieces of bread, truth that
we in our fallen condition could handle.
They were but crumbs from the master's
[music] heavenly table that had fallen
to the earth. But now what is set before
us is a feast fit for kings. Our
understanding of the cross now unveils
layers [music] of insights our earthly
minds would have been unable to
comprehend. Just as our earthly
intellects [music] could never fully
grasp eternity. They would have reeled
at the truths we now learn. The human
language of the old earth was
insufficient [music] to express or
appreciate the depths of these truths.
Throughout the city, small [music] group
studies are a common sight. In the old
New York, the old Los Angeles and other
cities around the world, it was typical
[music] to see individuals preaching on
street corners while the masses ignored
them. But here on these heavenly street
corners, [music] groups of heavenly
beings can be seen glorifying God and
studying together the science of
salvation. [music] It is extraordinary
to listen to angels dissect the plan of
salvation. To hear beings [music] from
other worlds share their insights on
God's glory, the saga of the conflict
that brewed in heaven, [music] the
salvific mission of the divine godhead,
and the science of love. At times, these
[music] sessions are punctuated with
reverent silence, while at other times
they are filled with joyful praise and
excitement. And when angels lift their
voices in song during these small
gatherings, the sound is [music]
transcendent beyond any earthly
comparison.
To us, heaven feels like an academic
institution, but far removed from any
mundanity. The new skills we acquire,
the numerous [music] schools scattered
throughout heaven, the new fields of
science we explore, the creative arts we
study, all surpass anything the finest
education [music] institutions on earth
could offer. There is a vast expanse of
knowledge to immerse ourselves in and an
eternity [music] to do so. We don't just
know automatically, we learn. And there
is so much to learn, so [music] much to
study, so much of what I was never good
at on Earth, geology, mathematics, art,
music, [music]
all now beckon my attention. And I have
eternity to study these. To think that
this is just a glimpse of what
transpires here in the new Jerusalem.
[music] If I were to add all the things
to do, the places to see, and the
sciences to study in the other cities,
nations, and worlds scattered across the
expanse [music] of God, there would not
be enough space in all of heaven's
diaries to contain them. Even in my
glorified state, the magnificence of it
all often leaves me speechless. [music]
[music]
We have entered [music] into a new phase
in the hearings. Up to this point, we
have been reviewing the fall of Lucifer
from heaven and [music] the conflict
that ensued on earth. We have tracked
the workings of God throughout the Old
Testament up to the death, burial,
[music] resurrection, and ascension of
Christ. The kings are informed that the
trial will now focus on the [music] plot
of Satan to counter the work that Christ
accomplished at the cross. We will see
how he attempted to [music] misconstrue
the purpose of Christ's sacrifice. The
jury must first fully understand what
Christ's death actually accomplished. As
the courtroom goes into vision, all seem
to be transported to the scene of
Christ's crucifixion. Understanding
enlightens our minds as we behold the
cross, [music] just as it did when we
beheld it by faith while living on the
old earth. At once, we see [music] that
the cross was the center point between
eternity past and eternity future.
Understanding what led to and happened
[music] after that center point was
critical in this case. The spirit
silently impresses on us that the law
Lucifer transgressed in heaven was the
law of love. Ezekiel [music] 28:15,
1 John 3:4, Romans 13:8. As long as
angels [music] kept this law, heaven
remained an atmosphere of love. Psalms
103:20.
This same law was written in the hearts
of Adam and Eve when they came forth
[music] from the hand of God, and he
breathed into them the breath of life.
But when they indulged in selfishness in
the garden, this law was broken. Since
the fall, man's heart would only [music]
grow more rebellious and hardened to the
law of God. Romans 8:es 6-10. Humanity
had grown so ignorant of the [music] law
of love toward God and neighbor that God
had to define love by writing out ten
commandments at Mount Si. The first four
commandments described love [music] for
God. Exodus 20 1-1. While the last six
defined love for one's neighbor, [music]
Exodus 20:12-17.
This law served as a description of sin.
It was written on stone to show the
[music] hardness of men's hearts. Those
who broke it were guilty of death. But
God provided a temporary remedy or
prescription for the transgression of
this law. This prescription, a second
law, [music] was called the law of Moses
because unlike the ten commandments, it
was written by the hand of Moses. This
temporary [music] prescription included
sacrifices, offerings, and feast days
that all had to be observed in the
Jewish temple in Jerusalem. These
[music] rituals served as the mode by
which Israel could gain forgiveness
under the old covenant. Gentiles who
recognized that they too were guilty of
breaking the law of love and wanted
[music] access to this temporary remedy
had to first be circumcised and become
part of the nation of Israel. [music]
Exodus 12:48 and 49. The courtroom now
fully understands that the death of
Jesus revealed the sacredness and
unchanging nature of the law of God.
Lucifer argued in heaven that this law
was not needed. Yet God would not enull
or change it, [music] but instead remove
Satan and his angels from heaven for
refusing to abide by it. Its
transgression led to death and Satan was
under this penalty. Ezekiel 28:1 [music]
19. Now at the cross, Satan would
attempt to show that God was partial and
inconsistent. [music] Would he now allow
his own son to die to uphold the penalty
of the law? Or would he enull the law
instead to [music] save his son from
death? To lay aside the law on behalf of
his son would have proven [music]
Satan's argument that the law was
arbitrary. But no, the death of Christ
demonstrated that the law of heaven
could in no way be abolished or
abregated, not [music] even to save the
life of the redeemer himself. These
commandments were eternal and applicable
to all people in all ages and in all
places. [music]
In dying, Jesus fulfilled the law of
love by laying his life down for the
world. This ultimate act of love would
plant the principle of the law back into
the hearts [music] of men. For only by
love can love be awakened. 1 John 4:19.
Through his death, [music] he not only
magnified the commandments of God, but
also replaced the old prescription for
sin, the law of Moses, with a new and
more powerful cure, that of his own
blood. This cure would be available to
anyone anywhere in the world. [music] No
longer was salvation to be bound up in
Jerusalem. No longer did one need to be
circumcised to gain access to the
[music] remedy. Christ would become the
Gentile circumcision, granting them free
access to his blood regardless of their
location.
>> [music]
>> 1 Corinthians 7:19, Galatians 5:6,
Colossians 2:11. The old prescription
had been nailed to the cross at the
death of Christ. [music]
Yet many of the Jews would reject the
new remedy and instead continue to trust
in the now useless and ineffective old
[music] prescription when God allowed
the destruction of Jerusalem and the
temple in 70 AD. It was designed to
signify that Christ was [music] in fact
the only remedy for sin, as sacrificing
bulls and goats at the temple was now no
longer possible.
>> [music]
>> Colossians 2:14-16,
Matthew 24:1 and2 Many among the jury
learned for the first time that [music]
Satan's strategy was to make it appear
that the death of Christ on the cross
not only got rid of the prescription for
[music] sin, the law of Moses, but also
that which describes and reveals sin,
the Ten Commandments. [music] Thus, the
deceptive argument went that Christians
no longer needed to live by any law
because they were under grace instead of
grace being the means by which man
[music] received forgiveness and could
again live in harmony with God's law
through the power and indwelling of the
spirit. [music] It now became the
license to sin freely without
consequence. He would push the idea that
grace nullified the law of God, and
would even go [music] so far as to claim
that a new and so-called better law, the
law of Christ, [music] represented
liberty from any law or righteous
requirement for the Christian. Yet, it
was Christ himself who gave the Ten
Commandments. 1 Corinthians 10:1-4,
Christ had come to [music] magnify this
law, not destroy it. Isaiah 42 21.
[music] The idea that the law of Christ
replaced the Ten Commandments was a
vague teaching used to promise professed
Christians personal liberty [music] to
decide for themselves what was right and
what was wrong. While also holding that
under the new covenant, [music] there
was no longer any consequence for the
violation of God's law. He would use the
same deceit that led Adam and Eve into
the sin of self-righteousness.
You can be holy like God,
>> knowing the difference between good and
evil for yourself. You don't need to
obey his word to do this. You are
already righteous and you will not die
nor will you be punished for
disregarding [music] his law.
>> Christians began echoing Satan's claim
in heaven that righteous people did not
need a law to govern holiness and that
[music] they could determine for
themselves what was right and wrong. But
all such who embraced this theory were
they here now would have objected in
this very court as they had done on
earth to the very law we are now using
to condemn Satan, his angels and the
lost. They would have literally been the
devil's [music] advocates in this
courtroom. In rejecting the law of God
as binding, professed Christians openly
declared themselves unfit for jury
[music] duty since jurors must be
law-abiding law upholding citizens of
the kingdom of heaven. Revelation 22:14.
Over the next 2,000 years of church
history, after the cross, we would see
[music] Satan wage war on the law of God
in the testimony of Jesus, trying to
deceive as many as he could over one or
both of [music] these points. Revelation
12:17. But at every age, God would have
people who, though not perfect, would
stand as faithful watchmen, calling out
the deceptions [music] of Satan and
calling all who would listen to come out
of these errors. Revelation 18:1-4. With
everyone on the same page about the
purpose and nature of the [music] cross,
we proceed on a journey in the courtroom
that takes us to the second coming of
Jesus, the event that brought us all
here. With each passing session, [music]
that which seems shrouded in mystery is
made plain to us, and God's justice,
mercy, love, and righteousness [music]
become more and more transparent.
So much here is beyond what I could have
expected. The city, for example, is
filled with children playing in the
streets and in the air. Some are
reunited and raised by one or both of
their parents, while others have no
parents here and are raised by angels
instead. Some of [music] these children
died at a young age, snatched by
disease, accident, or violence which
took them away too soon. Others were
among those who were translated without
seeing death at the second coming of
Jesus. 1 Thessalonians 4:13-17.
On earth, the death of any child brought
unspeakable grief to family, friends,
and even strangers. I have met here
millions of children who suffered
unspeakable fates in the past life.
These calamities would often lead to the
question, even among Christians, where
is God? Why doesn't he intervene? To us,
it was an inconsolable loss to imagine
living the rest of one's life without
their child. But here in heaven, these
looming questions that challenged our
faith now seem so irrelevant and
insignificant as we watch the joy and
laughter of these children in the
presence of God. Parents robbed of the
opportunity to watch their children grow
now pick up where they left off. The
children often swarm Jesus asking him
[music] all kinds of adorable questions.
These children will grow up here and
have the eternal privilege of never
suffering again.
>> [music]
>> Young children and teenagers who were
bullied, who had few friends on Earth,
have best friends here, scores [music]
of them. Some naturally gravitate
together as their likes, passions, and
hobbies are similar. Some connect
[music] because of their past
experiences on earth, but in light of
the glory of God, all the suffering and
heartache that seemed insurmountable now
appear [music] as nothing in our sight.
Philippians 3:8. What intrigues us the
most is the fact that even these
children are as captivated by the court
[music] proceedings as we adults are by
it. The irony is that here, even as
adults, we are actually still children.
Many of us entered eternal life being
less than 100 years old. Those of the
redeemed who lived prior to the flood
are older by several hundred years. But
[music] in the sight of eternity, we are
all practically children and will remain
so for a long, long time, [music]
especially in the eyes of the angels. We
will all continue to grow and learn in
understanding and wisdom and to some
extent even in our physical stature.
[music] It is the joy of heaven to take
these young ones under our wings and
explore other worlds with them, to fly
with, talk with, and guide them. Their
[music] presence lights up heaven, and
their joy is contagious. Not a sorrow
from the old earth darkens their
countenance.
All is swallowed up [music] by the
glories of heaven.
Without fail, our courtroom questions
and answers sessions always provide the
jurors with clarity and a better
understanding of this massive case.
[music] In one of our most intriguing
sessions, we discussed why the new
heavens and earth were not established
after Jesus conquered the grave. If
everything was [music] finished at the
cross, why would the world have
continued to exist for thousands of
years more? We learned that when [music]
Christ cried out, "It is finished," he
was only referring to his work as the
lamb of God. There was still [music] a
work for Christ to do, no longer as the
sacrificial lamb, but now as our high
priest, who [music] would make
intercession on our behalf. Hebrews 8:1
Hebrews 9:11. Though through his
sacrifice, salvation had been freely
offered. For it to [music] take effect,
it must be received in the heart of the
repentant believer. God would force
salvation on no one. Christ's disciples
[music] would embark upon the great
gospel commission by bringing the good
news to as many as would receive it.
Matthew 28:19, John 1:12,
Christ would intercede, [music]
sending the Spirit to assist all who
accepted his offer to take up the cross
and fight the [music] good fight of
faith. The finished work of the cross
would give way to the new work of
intercession. This work [music] would be
vital since Satan would contest every
decision made for Christ and seek to
dissuade by force or bribery all who
claim [music] to love him. 2 Timothy
3:12,
Hebrews 7:25, [music]
Jude 24.
Christ's work in heaven would involve
sending [music] the spirit of truth into
the world to combat Satan's lies
designed to confuse minds and distort
the character of God. John 14:17.
[music]
The gospel was to go into all the world,
but Satan [music] would attempt to
hijack and counterfeit this gospel with
a false one. Colossians 1:7 and8 2
Corinthians [music] 11:13-14
Christ's intercession would be crucial
in this battle between truth and error,
good and evil, [music] light and
darkness. It would revolve around
keeping the truths taught in the
sanctuary in the minds of all those who
believed. Satan would [music] try to
nullify Christ's intercession by seeking
to destroy faith in Christ's sacrifice,
defile anyone who claimed to be cleansed
and born again, pervert [music] the word
of God, disrupt the prayers of the
saints, destroy the light of the
Christian church, [music] and eliminate
or change God's law. Without the
intercession of Christ, the church would
have stood no chance against the
centuries long demonic onslaught about
to be waged against it.
[music]
Today we are going to hear firsthand
testimony from the martyrs who lived
during the period of the early centuries
under Roman persecution. [music]
Their testimonies are riveting in that
these saints sealed their witness in
[music] blood. We will now get to hear
their firsthand accounts as they now
live to tell about it. These believers
endured the most intense persecution
[music] against Christians with the
exception of what happened in the final
days and weeks just before Jesus second
coming. [music] The Roman Empire
considered Christianity a threat to its
stability. Refusal to adhere to Roman
authority in all things was seen as an
act of hostility toward [music] the
government. Rome desired that both civil
and religious obedience be rendered to
Caesar, [music] something Christians
knew they could not do without breaking
the commandment to have no other gods
before God. But behind this persecution
was the dragon, Satan himself, who
inspired this national hatred toward
those who [music] kept the commandments
of God and had the testimony of Jesus.
As these former martyrs share their
testimonies, [music] the court is moved
by their exhibition of faith.
Mesmerized, we listen to story after
story of Rome's cruelty as they devise
the most torturous method of death
[music] in an attempt to get Christians
to give up their faith in Jesus. We
listened to those who were burned alive
in coliseums [music] to the cheers of
onlookers. We asked them, "What was it
that kept you faithful and unafraid of
death?" [music] Many of them testified
that they had asked God to strengthen
them to drink of the cup. And as they
came closer to their deaths, they
[music] had been strengthened to endure.
Revelation 2:10.
Those who had been [music] given over to
lions and torn to pieces reported that
the peace of the spirit came over them.
By faith, they caught a glimpse of
heaven as they died. Knowing that
[music] Jesus had risen from the dead
and that he had prophesied this
persecution and yet promised eternal
life gave them courage to withstand all
the attacks Satan brought against them.
[music] John 15:20.
Satan's accusation was that these
Christians only serve God because he
protected them. If faced with death,
they would certainly break their [music]
allegiance to him. Rather, what was
proven was the strength of the
believer's love, which [music] was
stronger than death. In the end, the
work that Christ had accomplished in
just 3 and 1/2 years had produced a
people who were willing to die for him
just as he [music] had died for them.
These former martyrs learn in heaven
that their faithfulness in death was
seed that produced a massive harvest. As
unbelievers looked on [music] and saw
the light of the peace that passes
understanding light up their faces. It
led to thousands of conversions. [music]
In our courtroom, thousands stand to
their feet as the martyrs speak. These
standing ones were either directly or
indirectly influenced by the deaths of
those [music] now testifying. We are
here, they say, because of the powerful
witness of the martyr's love [music] for
Jesus. What we learn from this is that
despite Satan's strategy to destroy
Christianity by force, [music] his
efforts failed. We learn that even in
times when it seemed like God was not
present, he was in fact [music] working
out the greatest good. As we look at the
masses that are now present from the
martyrdom of others, we are blown away.
In some cases, one man, one woman's
death, [music] often in some small
obscure community, could produce
sometimes hundreds of new souls who had
given their lives to Christ. We see now,
not by faith, but by sight, that it is
[music] in fact true. All things work
together for good to them that love God,
to them who are the called according to
his purpose. And all heaven breaks out
in praise to God.
It is a stunning thing to watch the
birth of evil. In the past, we watch the
rise of evil in the holy atmosphere of
heaven as Lucifer sought to set up a new
government, a coup in which he would
rule over all creation. We watched the
origin of evil on a perfect earth as
Satan led Adam and Eve to try to be like
God without obeying his laws. Now we
were about to trace the origin of the
mystery of iniquity, the antichrist
system and its rise from within [music]
the New Testament church. Acts 20:29 to
32 1 Peter 2 [music] 1. As Satan saw
that the persecuting fires of Rome only
served to spread the gospel, he would
revert to his preferred method using
righteousness as a disguise for evil.
When the emperor Constantine came to
power, he converted to Christianity and
[music] sought to make it the state
religion. What was once a persecuted
minority now finds itself in a position
of power and influence.
This led to mass conversions, many of
which were not genuine. Pagans brought
[music] their superstitions and
paganistic teachings into the church and
thus began a compromise. Many of the
pagans [music] statues and images were
renamed as church saints and the very
first law was passed which required the
observance of the first [music] day of
the week. A day dedicated to worship of
the sun. God had officially replaced the
seventh day Sabbath of God. This [music]
union of church and state was the seed
that would create the system responsible
for the [music] most massive persecution
campaign against God's people. The rise
of this movement was described in the
books of Daniel and Revelation. The
church would become drunk on power.
Revelation 18:3 and [music] through its
influence bring the name of God into
contempt. At first, the church was under
the protection of the Roman Empire. But
when the Roman Empire fell, the church
[music] remained and became the sole
power in Rome, which then began to rule
nations around it. Now the church ruled
[music] the state. It is under this
power dynamic that would arise the
little horn who would persecute the
saints of the most high think to change
God's law and exercise authority for
1,260 years. [music]
Daniel 7:25.
The genius behind this deception was
that it was all being done under the
guise of Christianity. [music] And for
the next 1,200 years, this church system
rising out of the fallen Roman Empire
[music] would do more to damage the
truths of the Bible and the name and
character of God than any atheist
[music] or skeptic of the Bible could
ever think to imagine. And just as Satan
in heaven had launched an attack on the
law of God under a disguise of holiness,
so he [music] would through this church
system amplify that war under the same
disguise. Yet Christ's work as man's
heavenly intercessor would play a
crucial role in exposing this deception
and restoring [music] the truth that
would then be taken into the whole
world. In fulfillment of the great
commission, the court [music] adjourns
as we praise God for his intercession
that helped open the eyes of countless
millions who were once misled by Satan's
[music] deceptions and lies.
Another session begins. We now review
the history of the dark ages. The year
is 538. [music] It is the beginning of
the Byzantine papacy. The pope has been
declared by Justinian's decree to be the
head of all churches and the corrector
of heretics.
The organization has amassed power
beyond what it could have imagined just
a few hundred years earlier. [music]
When Constantine made Christianity the
state religion, pagans flocked to the
church. Teachings foreign to the Bible
became commonplace [music]
and led to the formation of strange
doctrines. These doctrines attacked the
high priestly work [music] of Christ as
represented by the sanctuary furniture.
The prophet Daniel foresaw that this
power would attack and cast down the
truth of Christ's priestly intercession
in the sanctuary. Daniel 8:es 10 to 12.
The altar of sacrifice, also known as
the altar of burnt offering, upon which
an animal was slain every morning and
evening, taught the truth that the wages
of sin was death. However, the church
began teaching that the wages of sin was
not actually death, but rather eternal
life in hell. The [music] doctrine,
which came to be known as purgatory,
rested on the false pagan belief that
the soul was naturally immortal and
could not die. Despite the clear
teaching that immortality was granted
only to those who accept Christ and was
granted at resurrection, not death. 1
John 3:15, 1 Corinthians 15:es 52 to 54,
[music] Ezekiel 18:4.
This error of the wages of sin being an
eternally burning hell was problematic.
If this was the penalty of sin, then the
whole world would be lost. For Christ
did not pay that penalty. He did not die
eternally and is not now suffering in
hell. He was dead for 3 days and proves
that the wages of sin is death, not
eternal torment. Death is asleep.
Ecclesiastes 9:56. And this is the
penalty Jesus paid. The Bible taught
that eternal life was a gift only to the
righteous and that this gift was
received not at death but at the
resurrection. Therefore, sinners could
not burn forever simply because they
could not live forever. [music]
Genesis 3:22, Malachi 4:13. The church
also began to teach that the sacrifice
of Christ was not sufficient for the
forgiveness of sins. Instead, one had to
pay indulgences and perform penance to
be truly forgiven.
And as priests and bishops informed the
ignorant masses that God required money
for them to escape the fires of
purgatory, the church [music] got more
prosperous while the people began to see
God as a ruthless tyrant, just as Satan
would have it. Then there was the labor
which taught the truth of baptism,
[music] the church cast this truth down
to the ground by introducing infant
sprinkling based on the idea that if a
newborn child died, that child would be
sent to purgatory by a so-called loving
God. Infant [music] sprinkling was
presented as a means of saving babies
from the fires of hell and the wrath of
a vengeful god. This teaching bypassed
the necessity of repentance since an
infant could not repent and introduced
[music] the concept of sprinkling since
babies could not be baptized under
water. This bypassed repentance as a
means of salvation. [music] Next, to
maintain the spiritual ignorance of the
people, no common person was allowed to
possess a copy of [music] the Bible.
Thus, the truth represented by the table
of showbread was also cast down. Anyone
having a Bible could [music] be put to
death or punished with fines. In no sure
way could Satan cast down the truth than
by keeping the [music] bread of life out
of the hands of the people. The altar of
incense representing the priestly
intercession of Christ was replaced with
the confessional booth, a two
compartment room modeled after the
[music] sanctuary with a priest sitting
in the place of God claiming to have
power to forgive men's sins. Mark 2:7.
[music]
The seven branched candlestick which
represented the light of God's people
was essentially put out in darkness
[music]
as anyone who refused to go along with
the teachings of the church was
persecuted, burned at the stake.
Finally, [music] the truth regarding the
ark of the covenant where the law of God
was shown to be the foundation of his
throne was cast down to the ground. As
the church began [music] to teach, the
commandments of God could be changed.
The church removed the second
commandment's prohibition [music] and
began to allow the worship of images.
They also claimed to have the power to
change the Sabbath day from Saturday to
Sunday. This they did with boastful
statement after boastful statement.
It is well to remind the Presbyterians,
Baptists, Methodists, [music]
and all other Christians that the Bible
does not support them anywhere in their
observance of Sunday. Sunday is an
institution [music] of the Roman
Catholic Church, and those who observe
the day observe a commandment of the
Catholic Church. Priest Brady in an
address reported in the Elizabeth, New
Jersey [music] news on March 18th, 1903.
Protestants accept Sunday rather than
Saturday as the day for public worship
after the Catholic Church made the
change. But the Protestant mind does not
seem to realize that in observing
Sunday, they are accepting the authority
of the spokesman for the church, the
Pope. Our Sunday visitor, February 5th,
[music] 1950. The Roman Catholic Church
changed the observance of the Sabbath to
Sunday by right of the divine infallible
authority given to her by her founder
Jesus Christ. The Protestant claiming
the Bible to be the only guide of faith
has no warrant for observing Sunday. I
end this [music] matter. The 7th Day
Adventist is the only consistent
Protestant. He Catholic Universe
Bulletin [music] August 14th 1942 page
4. Perhaps the boldest thing, the most
revolutionary change the church ever did
happened in the first century. [music]
The holy day, the Sabbath was changed
from Saturday to Sunday. The day of the
Lord Das Dominica was chosen not from
any directions noted in the [music]
scriptures, but from the church's sense
of its own power. The day of
resurrection, the day of Pentecost
[music] 50 days later, came on the first
day of the week. So this would be the
new Sabbath. People who think that the
scriptures should be [music] the sole
authority should logically become 7th
Day Adventists and keep Saturday [music]
holy. Sentinel Pastors Paige St.
Catherine Catholic Church Algan Michigan
May 21st 1995. [music]
Finally, the church taught that a man
could hold the title of holy father, God
manifest in the flesh [music] and
boasted of it, saying, "All names which
in the scriptures are applied to Christ,
by virtue of which it is established
that he is over the church, [music] all
the same names are applied to the pope."
Robert Bellery, disputations to
controversies on the authority of
councils, chapter 17, 1628 edition,
volume 1, p 266. [music]
The Pope is not only the representative
of Jesus Christ, but he is Jesus Christ
himself, hidden under the veil [music]
of flesh. Catholic National July 1895.
For over,200 years, the church
persecuted the saints of the most high.
Any Christian who saw through her errors
and refused to drink of them wasounded.
All of these teachings and abuses would
finally lead to the French Revolution, a
wholesale rejection of the church,
[music] the Bible, and religion in the
form of atheism. And it was during this
revolution that France would abolish the
papal states [music] temporarily
wounding the papacy. That year was 1798,
exactly 1,260
[music] years from 538 AD, just as
prophecy had foretold. Daniel 7:25,
[music]
Ezekiel 4:6, Revelation 13:5. This was
mystery Babylon, the masterpiece of
[music] deception. Paul had forewarned
of the man of sin sitting in the temple
of God, showing himself that he is God.
2 Thessalonians [music]
2:es 2-10, but for the intercessory work
of Christ as high priest, sending light
and truth through the Holy Spirit to
enlighten his people. The amazing
[music] events that took place over a
span of 500 years, beginning in the 13th
century, to counter this massive and
global deception would have never
occurred. These are the events we focus
on in [music] our next hearing.
The Protestant [music] Reformation. The
famed Catholic priest John Wliffe is the
first to take the stand. He is a hero
here. His response [music] to the spirit
sent by Jesus intercessory work led him
to translate the Bible into English. In
the year 1382, he [music] put his life
on the line to put the bread of life,
the word of God, into the hands of the
common people. [music] The church had
been able to practice and prosper in its
error and darkness by keeping the Bible
locked away from the public. Wliffe,
nicknamed the morning [music] star of
the reformation, brought the light of
the word to the people, and this light
would be used to expose the darkness
[music] and errors of the church. The
table of showbread representing the word
of God had been effectively restored.
[music]
And it was this act that started the
Protestant Reformation. So powerful was
White Cliff's work against darkness that
long after his death, [music] the church
dug up his bones and burned them,
condemning him as a heretic. Yet this
unjust declaration would be reversed in
the courts of heaven. It is why he
stands here now justified [music] while
his accusers are absent. We listen as
Wikliffe eloquently testifies how the
spirit given [music] by Christ empowered
him in the face of opposition to do the
work he was called to do. He was
faithful to the present truth of his
time that the word of God was given for
all people not just to priests to be
read and interpreted. Next, [music]
Martin Luther takes the stand
representing the 15 and 1600s. Luther
[music]
through the intercession of Christ came
into the light of justification by
faith. He testifies of being nearly
driven to the point of hopelessness
[music] as he felt that he had not done
enough to be forgiven and speaks with
riveting emotion of the moment he was
ascending [music] the Scala sancta.
On his hands and knees, 28 broad marble
stairs claimed to be the very steps
Jesus [music] walked on when sentenced
by Pilate in Jerusalem. Repeating his
prayers on each step in hopes [music] of
receiving the promised indulgence of the
church. In that moment, Luther grasped
the truth symbolized by the altar of
sacrifice. [music] Faith in Christ's
sacrifice for the sinner was the only
justification for salvation. Habacook 2
[music] 4. This realization led this
Catholic monk to embrace the teaching
and in turn offer hope [music] to
millions who were then living without
hope and had labored unsuccessfully to
attain peace in the attempt to earn
salvation by their own works or money.
Thrilled with holy awe, we watch that
day, [music] October 31st, 1517, as
Luther nails his 95 thesis on the church
[music] doors in Vittenberg, Germany,
officially marking the beginning of the
Protestant Reformation. Again, [music]
the church did all it could to silence
the voice and still the pen of Luther.
[music]
But because of Christ's intercession,
which strengthened him, he was able to
fulfill the mission God had called him
to, that of restoring the truth taught
by the altar of sacrifice, the just
[music] shall live by faith. John
Calvin, Luther's contemporary, now takes
the stand and begins to testify of how
the intercession of Christ moved him to
study the art of intercession [music]
and prayer. Calvin testifies of his
passion for prayer and how this passion
would lead to the truth that man could
pray [music] directly to God without the
need for human intercessors or saints.
Calvin's work within the Protestant
Reformation [music] would restore the
connection between man and God in prayer
symbolized by the [music] altar of
incense. His institutes of the Christian
religion would impact millions and show
them how to [music] connect with their
high priest Jesus Christ. Following
Calvin, John Smith, who lived in the
1600s and founded the Baptist Church,
now [music] takes the stand.
Through Christ's intercession, Smith
would be convicted of the truth
regarding baptism, that it was an
[music] act that should be carried out
in connection with repentance and that
it was by total immersion, not
sprinkling. [music] Infants could not
repent and therefore should not be
baptized.
Smith testifies of how the spirit led
him to this truth. [music] And as each
speaks, we see why Christ's work as high
priest was so crucial. Not only was he
still [music] calling all who desired to
be saved to accept his blood, but he was
also directing and protecting [music]
his church from the mystery of iniquity.
John Wesley now takes the stand
representing the key influencer of the
1700s and testifies [music] of what led
him to start the Methodist Church. His
passion for witnessing, for letting
one's light shine, was [music] in
essence restoring the candlestick
representing the missionary work of the
believers. His emphasis on godly living
and godly witnessing would restart and
ignite the spreading of the restored
gospel to fulfill the great commission
given by [music] Christ. But this could
not be entirely done without the
restoration of the last article of the
sanctuary, the ark of the covenant
containing the law of God.
>> [music]
>> This final movement would bring us down
to the 1800s where through the
intercession of Christ, the restoration
of his law [music] would be the final
piece of the gospel to be repaired.
And there would be one last push to
preach the restored gospel to every
nation, kindred, tongue, and people.
Revelation 14:6.
This history [music]
rich in salvation demonstrated God's
protection and care over his people and
his [music] truth. Revealing that for
every assault of the enemy, God would
respond to make a way of escape from
error into [music] truth. The court
adjourns as we stand amazed at God's
efforts to save humanity.
[music]
Christ's intercession in the restoration
of the truths of the gospel as each
reformer took the stand [music] and
testified of the influence of the Holy
Spirit in moving them into action. The
atmosphere in the courtroom was
electric. Now we were about to witness
the final movement that Christ through
his intercession would bring to the
scene to restore the broken law. As we
watch the heaven vision, we are taken to
the years just before 1844. [music]
Unlike the previous movements, there is
no single individual to call forth.
Prominent [music] teachers, pastors, and
theologians from almost every existing
denomination as well as from [music]
multiple nations stand to testify to one
single point. They all testify of the
moving of the spirit that [music]
brought their attention to focus at the
same time independent of one another on
the prophecy of Daniel 8 verse 13 and
14.
This testimony reveals that the interest
in [music] this prophecy was coordinated
by God himself. These witnesses testify
that they were unanimously united on the
2300 [music] day prophecy, concluding
sometime in 1844.
Despite their denominational
differences, [music]
most testify that they had thought it
was the return of Jesus, but confessed
that they were mistaken. In actuality,
[music] it was the revelation of the
final movement to bring attention to the
last article of furniture yet to be
restored, the ark of the covenant
containing [music] the law of God. With
the law being restored to its rightful
place, God would begin to [music] select
the jury. Those who in every age since
Adam had remained faithful to him
[music] and faithful to truth. the
everlasting gospel which pointed to
these six truths. The sacrifice of
[music] Christ, the baptism of the
spirit, the power of his word, the
intercession of Christ, the light
shining through prophecy [music] in
God's people, and the law and mercy of
God would then be presented in a
unformed [music] message that was to
prepare the world for the second coming
of Christ. We watch as three [music]
angels are commissioned to circle the
earth with the messages of the
everlasting gospel, announcing that
[music] the hour of God's judgment had
come, followed by a warning against the
teachings of Babylon and the receiving
of the mark of the beast. Revelation
14:6-14.
This message was God's final appeal to
the world, much as it was in the days of
Noah. Thousands and thousands received
this completed gospel [music] while even
more defied and rejected it all while
claiming to be followers of God. Their
anger and hatred was particularly
directed toward the law of God. But more
specifically, [music] they rejected the
Sabbath commandment and chose rather to
observe and uplift the counterfeit
version instituted by the traditions of
men.
We see that [music] once the Church of
the Dark Ages began to teach that the
law of God could be changed in the
slightest degree. [music] It was only a
small step to many Protestant churches
teaching the abolishment of the entire
law. Many championed this [music] era
which in essence set them against God
and his law, setting the stage for a
final conflict that [music] would
involve the whole world and prepare the
way for the coming of the kings of the
east, Christ and his heavenly armies.
Revelation 16:13.
The time of trouble such as never was
came upon the world as an overwhelming
surprise. Watching the replay of Earth's
final scene in the courtroom is
emotional for us on many different
levels. The redeemed jurors at last get
to see the ripening and end result of
the principles of Satan's rebellion
which began in heaven. [music] The
deception had been so deeply laid, the
plot so perfectly calculated that it
exposed [music] with clarity all who had
not truly submitted themselves to the
will and truth of God. The witnesses who
now [music] take the stand are those who
lived through it or had faithfully given
their lives. During this final conflict,
the final events of Earth's history
began to unfold simultaneously [music]
with the going forth of the fully
restored, unadulterated gospel. The
churches that had ultimately rejected
the preaching of this message became
designated as Babylon. [music]
Revelation 14:8. And as the beast that
had horns like a lamb, but spoke like a
dragon. Revelation 13:1. These symbols
pointed [music] to those who professed
to follow the lamb, but in actuality
espoused the lawlessness of the dragon.
Satan had crafted a slow and deliberate
process of leading the churches of earth
to focus more and more on an earthly
nationalism and less and less of the
heavenly [music] kingdom. The churches
in the most powerful nation on earth
began to desire forcing Christianity on
society in the name of Jesus. Of course,
they thought [music] they were doing
God's service. But because they did not
know Jesus, they did not understand that
love and righteousness cannot be forced.
The ones who had been bent on this idea
of earthly dominionism revealed the same
heart Lucifer had in heaven. [music] The
desire to rule by force in the name and
under the guise of holiness. Yet
thousands of unbelievers revolted
against any such idea of making the
world a Christian theocracy. Skeptics,
atheists, and people from other
religions united in opposing this false
movement within Christianity to convert
the world through legislation. They saw
this as a mere repeat and image to the
church of the dark ages which had done
that exact thing using political power
to persuade the masses to serve God.
Many of God's people, students of
prophecy throughout the ages, had known
that the Bible prophesied that the
entire world would unite against the
people of God. We knew this was called
the time of trouble. Daniel 12:12. What
many of us could not understand was how
a world so divided in beliefs would
ultimately unite to fight against those
who keep the commandments of God and
have the faith of Jesus. Revelation
12:17. Those of us not living in these
final days find out here in the court
exactly what or rather exactly who was
able to unite skeptics, religionists of
all kinds with Babylon, the system of
fallen churches across the globe. It was
in fact Satan counterfeiting the
appearing of Christ. The day it happened
took the world by surprise. The fallen
Christian churches who had embraced
false teachings were not aware that when
Christ returned the second time, it
would neither be secret nor invisible.
Matthew 24:27.
They did not know that when Jesus came
again, his feet would not touch the
ground. But instead, he would stop in
the air and call the saints up to meet
him in the sky, taking them with him to
heaven for a thousand years. 1
Thessalonians 4:13-17,
Revelation 20:4 and 5, John 14:1-3.
Thus, when Satan appeared as a being of
life, pretending to be Christ at his
second coming. 2 Thessalonians 2:4.
[music] While his feet touched the
earth, claiming to set up the millennial
kingdom on earth, the unstudied
Christian church received him as Jesus.
He had now accomplished on earth what he
attempted in heaven to be worshiped as
the most high. Isaiah 14:12.
But he did not come alone. When Jesus
[music] returns, the dead are raised to
life. So to complete this masterpiece of
deception, Satan's fallen angels [music]
impersonate the dead. Revelation 16:13.
This overwhelming miracle convinces even
the skeptic, the atheist, the stubborn
unbeliever who swore [music] they would
never believe unless they saw. Now
seeing is believing. and the entire
world. Muslims, atheists, fallen
Christianity, Jews, Buddhists,
agnostics, and everyone in between bow
at the foot of this counterfeit messiah.
Because the Christian churches were led
to believe that the 1,000-year rule
would take place on this earth. They
were ripe for the ultimate deception of
Satan pretending to be Christ and
ushering in this period. This impostor
tells them that the sign of allegiance
to his millennial kingdom on earth is
the Sabbath. and that from one new moon
to another and from one Sabbath to
another all flesh is to come before him
to worship. Isaiah 66:12 and 13. By
this, however, he means the first day of
the week instead of the seventh day.
[music]
This is his attempt to lead the whole
world to worship him as the creator
through observing a false Sabbath in
dedication to himself. Those who refuse
him, who see through this charade are
they [music] that keep the commandments
of God and have the faith of Jesus. They
know this is a counterfeit and in saying
this they incur the wrath and vitriol of
his deceived believers [music] as if
they are blaspheming Christ himself.
This false Jesus then tells the masses
that those who refuse to obey him
[music] are blasphemous and are worthy
of death and should not be privileged to
buy or sell. [music] Revelation 13:15
to17, he tells them that these are the
wicked ones whom are to be judged during
the 1,000 years on earth, and peace
comes only as these rebellious ones are
eliminated. How powerful a deception he
leads the wicked to think they were the
righteous ones who would judge on earth.
And just as the decree to kill those who
refuse to worship the beast in his image
[music]
or receive the mark of this antichrist,
it was then that I, who had been dead
for over 200 years, heard [music] the
words, "Awake! Awake!"
[music]
It is hard to believe the 1,000-year
judgment has come to an end.
We the jurors have all come to know each
other by name. We know each other's
stories. [music] We have traveled and
explored thousands of worlds and talked
and worshiped together. We have
fellowshipped [music] with the Godhead
and learned much in the court of heaven.
We have watched scene after scene of the
controversy between Satan and Christ. We
have [music] brought to Jesus all of our
hard questions and have been satisfied
with his justice and mercy. We now know
without any doubt [music] why the lost
are lost and the saved are saved. There
is no question, no uncertainty in the
minds of the jurors. God is just in
every decision he has ever made.
And now the time has come. For the last
several years, preparations have been
underway for the transport [music] of
the city of God to the earth made new.
The time has now come for all things are
ready. The kings in heaven, angels and
Jesus saddle [music] up on white horses.
The heavenly armies are preparing to
descend once again to earth. This time
for the final battle, Gog and Magog,
[music]
a symbol representing all the wicked who
are left dead on the earth after the
first resurrection. Revelation [music]
25 and 6. They are to be resurrected as
the city of God descends. Here they will
stand before the throne of God for their
own [music] trial. The great white
throne judgment.
Revelation 20 11-12. [music] Here the
wicked will watch the scenes we have had
the privilege of viewing in heaven, but
they will see the [music] parts they
played and will see how they rejected
the mercies of God over and over. They
will acknowledge [music] the justice of
God just as we have. But for them, it
will be too late indeed. Every knee
shall bow and every tongue [music]
confess that Jesus is Lord. It is a
solemn time. We know that we will see
many of our family and friends on earth
and we know that this [music] is going
to be their ultimate end. Even now, our
eyes are welling up with tears. The city
of God [music] finally begins to move,
and the journey to the end of sinners
and sin. The old earth, as we knew it,
is now underway.
Just 1,000 years ago, we made our
journey across the universe to the city
of God. Angels [music] welcomed us into
our new home. Now, God was coming to
earth to make his home with us.
Revelation 21:es [music]
2 and 3. Warriors on white horses ride
in front, behind, beneath, and above the
city. We travel with less [music] speed
than we did coming here a thousand years
ago. While we are filled with the
excitement of returning to Earth, where
our eternal home will be, [music] there
is a somnity as we know what must take
place before this. The old earth and the
wicked must [music] be brought to a
complete end. Songs of celestial glory
fill the air as we travel. What a sight
to behold [music] as a massive army once
again fills the sky. These songs echoing
back and forth, [music] interspersed
with thunderous sounds of billions of
angels wings flapping and hooves beating
in harmonious rhythms. [music]
The fiery glory of God surrounds the
city. Jesus rides ahead of the entire
army. Revelation 19:14.
With every [music] world we pass, more
riders join us, expanding our number
beyond number. Unlike our journey here
which began with so many questions and
anticipation, [music] we return older,
wiser, every question answered and
settled forever as [music] to the
principles of truth and righteousness
and of the peril of sin and lawlessness.
The night universe [music] air feels
crisp and electric as the sense of love
for one another and the beginning of
eternity on earth fills our hearts.
Angels [music] sound their trumpets as
in the distance the old earth begins to
appear in sight. Though we are [music]
days out from it, we can see the
desolation and are reminded of the ruin
that we left a thousand years ago. The
time for the final battle is near. It is
a marvel to us that the wicked will
attempt to fight a battle [music] they
cannot win. But we know now this is what
sin does. It deceives those who embrace
it. But that deception [music] will soon
be swept away in the face of the great
white throne judgment. It is now time
for the final scene. And though we are
saddened by the final coming conflict,
the peace that awaits [music] us on the
coming newly recreated earth outshadows
it all. We are here for it and we are
ready. [music] By my side are my family
and friends. Those I had from earth and
those I've made in heaven. Even former
enemies of the gospel now [music] ride
with us as they had come to Christ
before their deaths or translation.
Those who had never heard of Christ,
[music] but lived lives in harmony with
the spirit, now fully understand and
embrace the person of Christ. The army,
[music] all dressed in regal clothing
and wrapped in glorious flames of love,
are made up of people from every nation,
color, and background. Former thieves,
[music] murderers, liars, criminals, all
made holy through the blood of Christ.
Now ride, ready to reinhabit the earth.
God's [music] original intention for man
to live forever and ever with him is
about to be realized. Our [music] 1,000
years in heaven feels to us like just
yesterday. A sudden realization hits me.
How is it possible to have experienced
this much love, [music] joy, peace, and
adventure all in what feels like just
one day? I think to myself, amazing.
Life has truly [music] only just begun.
>> [music]
>> Awake. Awake. This voice startles me out
of my sleep. I'm in an enclosed,
confined, dark space. I am confused. I
feel a sense of panic. My last memory
was that I was leaving church. Yes,
[music] I remember. I was leaving
Sabbath service when my car was hit. I
wonder at first if I am in a hospital or
resting in the night, but then I
realized that voice. It is him. And I
know I'm in the grave. Suddenly, I am
propelled upward. But instead of being
lifted into the air as I read about in
the Bible, I find myself standing on
earth. Something feels wrong about this.
I look at my hands. They are not the
hands I recognize. They are scarred,
rugged, rough, cold. I look around and
see millions of other people popping up
out of graves. Their appearance is
difficult to look upon. I look up to see
a city in the sky descending. The city
is glorious. I have studied the Bible
well enough to know that I should not be
here but there in the city. This is the
second resurrection and I have come up
with a wicked. How could this be? Why
has he not opened the city to me? I
[music] know the truth. I know Jesus.
This is unfair. Either way, it doesn't
matter now. He [music] is obviously my
enemy and I am now his. We deserve the
right to be in that city. [music] The
tree of life is there. If we here on
Earth band together combine our forces,
we can breach the city, gain access to
the tree, eat and live [music] forever.
This is now our only hope. And I get the
sense that we are ready to fight for it,
[music] to go up and possess the city.
Our numbers are massive. We are able. I
feel it. It is then that our eyes behold
a dazzling being among us. He tells us
that he is the Lord, the one who has
resurrected us. He tells us that the
city now descending is rightfully his,
and that we must fight for it. A wave of
conviction flows over me and I feel a
[music] connection to this dazzling
being like nothing I have ever felt
before. I realize that I must have been
deceived into believing the account of
the Bible. [music]
We must fight for ourselves and fight
against this unjust action. Yes, we are
ready to fight. Yes, we are ready to
follow our [music] leader. And yes, we
are ready to surround and possess this
city. The city is still a far off. It
will take us weeks [music] or more to
fully prepare for this war. But we're
confident. I will chronicle our
preparation and victory. And I'm sure
that this will go down as the greatest
[music] military campaign of all time.